<!-- prefuse graph writer :: Wed Dec 06 09:49:08 CST 2017 -->
<graph directed="0">
  <!-- nodes -->
  <node id="192">
    <att name="AB" value="We propose a new conceptual model for understanding technology evolution that highlights dynamic and highly interdependent relationships among multiple technologies. We argue that, instead of considering technologies in isolation, technology evolution is best viewed as a dynamic system or ecosystem that includes a variety of interrelated technologies. By considering the interdependent nature of technology evolution, we identify three roles that technologies play within a technology ecosystem. These roles are components, products and applications, and support and infrastructure. Technologies within an ecosystem interact through these roles and impact each others&apos; evolution. We also classify types of interactions between technology roles, which we term paths of influence. We demonstrate the use of our proposed model through examples of wireless networking (Wi-Fi) technologies and a business mini-case on the digital music industry."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Technology roles and paths of influence in an ecosystem model of technology evolution"/>
    <att name="name" value="192"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2007"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY &amp; MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="33"/>
  </node>
  <node id="129">
    <att name="AB" value="There is a growing need for measures assessing technological changes in systemic contexts as business ecosystems replace standalone products. In these ecosystem contexts, organizations are required to manage their innovation processes in increasingly networked and complex environments. In this paper, we introduce the technology and ecosystem clockspeed measures that can be used to assess the temporal nature of technological changes in a business ecosystem. We analyze systemic changes in the personal computer (PC) ecosystem, explicitly focusing on subindustries central to the delivery of PC gaming value to the end user. Our results show that the time-based intensity of technological competition in intertwined subindustries of a business ecosystem may follow various trajectories during the evolution of the ecosystem. Hence, the technology and ecosystem clockspeed measures are able to pinpoint alternating dynamics in technological changes among the subindustries in the business ecosystem. We subsequently discuss organizational considerations and theoretical implications of the proposed measures."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="BUSINESS ECOSYSTEMS&apos; EVOLUTION - AN ECOSYSTEM CLOCKSPEED PERSPECTIVE"/>
    <att name="name" value="129"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2013"/>
    <att name="SO" value="COLLABORATION AND COMPETITION IN BUSINESS ECOSYSTEMS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="8"/>
  </node>
  <node id="17">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper analyses the dynamics of platform business models as an entrepreneurial ecosystem and its effects on regional development. Here, we seek to answer the following research questions: (1) What effects do platform business models have on regional development? (2) What factors and structures affect the dynamics of platform business models? (3) How can we describe the dynamics of platform business models in app stores and hotel-booking industries? To answer these questions, the authors first analysed two platform entrepreneurial ecosystems in the smartphone app store industry (Google Play&apos;s Android market and Apple&apos;s App Store) and two ecosystems in the hotel-booking industry (Hotels.com and Booking.com). Second, we analysed the effects of platforms as entrepreneurial ecosystems on the regional development of Daegu Metropolitan City. We used in-depth interview methods with a semi-structured questionnaire, system dynamics (SD) simulation, a literature review, and a statistical analysis as research methods. The results of these analyses yielded the following findings. First, platform business models as economic ecosystems motivate a change of regional development from focused areas to multiple areas, from a hierarchical structure of firms to a network of diverse firms, and from scope and scale economy-based firms leading regional development to creative economy-based firms leading regional development. Second, we identified three category factors that were important in a platform ecosystem, and built up and simulated causal and SD models of these factors. Third, we found that the dynamics of platform ecosystems differ from platform to platform because the openness of platforms produces different effects on firms according to the industry to which they belong."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Growth of a platform business model as an entrepreneurial ecosystem and its effects on regional development"/>
    <att name="name" value="17"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="EUROPEAN PLANNING STUDIES"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="131">
    <att name="AB" value="Purpose - The purpose of this paper is to identify the dominant strategy and business models of companies and to analyse the awareness of design and the stage of design application in business in its broader sense from the perspective of business executives in the manufacturing sector and professional designers in the design industry that lead to creating successful business models in Latvia and Estonia. Design/methodology/approach - The questionnaire was used with two target groups business executives (based on NACE 2, B-E sections, ie. manufacturing companies) and professional designers in the design industry (NACE 2, M 74.10 section). In the first target group, 374 responses of business executives in Latvia and 371 responses of business executives in Estonia were received; in the second target group, 85 respondents in Latvia and 42 respondents in Estonia providing professional design services were analysed to identify the level of design awareness and its application in business in the respective countries. Findings - There are national and regional specifics in Latvia and Estonia based on the development level of micro and macro factors that influence the entire innovation ecosystem. When comparing both countries in these terms, both target groups specify that design is applied more frequently in the processes of product development in Estonia, thus leading to new forms of innovation, than it is in Latvia. Conversely, in Latvia, many business managers still focus on short-term business solutions and cost-reduction as a sole challenge, with limited awareness of management approaches based on the broader application of design as a powerful innovation source for product development, improvement, and renewal of business models. Research limitations/implications - A suggestion for further research is to replicate the study in Lithuania and explore the perspective of other stakeholders. Practical implications - The results of this research demonstrate the necessity to change the thinking patterns of business managers in order to develop their skills and capabilities to recognize emerging new driving forces of innovation unfolding through awareness of design and opportunities for its extended application that create successful business models for continuous value generation. Originality/value - This paper makes a contribution to understanding the current stage of awareness of design and its application in the manufacturing sector in the Baltic States."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The creation of successful business models through the extended application of design in business in Latvia and Estonia"/>
    <att name="name" value="131"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2013"/>
    <att name="SO" value="BALTIC JOURNAL OF MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="1"/>
  </node>
  <node id="82">
    <att name="AB" value="To succeed business around renewables and sustainability often need new types of business models. Business models are typically considered from the viewpoint of a focal firm, whereas renewables and sustainability often require a broader, system perspective. We explore how firms together in the energy business ecosystems develop their business models to facilitate change in the logic of the industry. Earlier studies on ecosystems have looked at the role of technical interdependencies in ecosystems, whereas we use a business model lens to study collaboration between companies. We use three cases from the distributed energy ecosystems to illustrate how different kinds of mechanisms trigger closer collaboration, sustainability and increased overall value creation. Our findings pinpoint the importance of identifying the factors driving the business models of the collaborating firms to facilitate system transitions and change in the logic of an industry. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Collaboration mechanisms for business models in distributed energy ecosystems"/>
    <att name="name" value="82"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF CLEANER PRODUCTION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="9"/>
  </node>
  <node id="76">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper explores the process of nurturing a business ecosystem to facilitate corporate growth in an unfamiliar foreign market with high product uncertainty and no network resources. The authors conducted a qualitative, longitudinal study by examining a successful business case ARM (a leader in microprocessor intellectual property) - to demonstrate how firms nurture their business ecosystems to develop in the Chinese market and to stimulate demand even without the advantages of resources and stabilized products. Based on the road map method, this paper develops a framework of creating a business ecosystem in three sequential stages namely, incubating complementary partners, identifying leader partners, and integrating ecosystem partners. The findings enrich classic international business and demand chain theories by highlighting different roles stakeholders adopt to cope with uncertain products in a foreign market. In practical terms, these findings also provide Mode 2 knowledge with application context (Gibbons et al., 1997) on entering new markets by building up an ecosystem. (C) 2015 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Nurturing business ecosystems for growth in a foreign market: Incubating, identifying and integrating stakeholders"/>
    <att name="name" value="76"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF INTERNATIONAL MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="2"/>
  </node>
  <node id="21">
    <att name="AB" value="Civic challenges such as urban mobility and energy problems offer new corporate innovation opportunities. However, such challenges are wicked and difficult to tame. They require novel solutions that account for and integrate contradictory perspectives within the local innovation ecosystem of firms, governments, and citizens. This article presents a successful civic innovation crowdsourcing project case study, in which multinational firm Bombardier encouraged a global civic crowd to co-create visionary solutions to the challenge of future mobility in crowded cities around the world. Bombardier recruited a global crowd of 900 individuals and facilitated the citizen development of more than 215 solutions of unique firm value. We explore the process and outcome of this crowdsourcing project and derive actionable design principles for a three-phased civic innovation crowdsourcing process including: (1) crowd construction, (2) crowd knowledge acquisition, and (3) crowd knowledge assimilation. This process enables the crowd to integrate members&apos; diverse and contradictory knowledge proactively at both the team and individual levels. Additionally, the crowd is able to balance extension of existing local solutions and exploration of path-breaking technologies and solution concepts. (C) 2016 Kelley School of Business, Indiana University. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Taming wicked civic challenges with an innovative crowd"/>
    <att name="name" value="21"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="BUSINESS HORIZONS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="34">
    <att name="AB" value="Purpose - The purpose of this paper is to identify the minimum conditions for the formation of an ecosystem that favours the emergence of spin-offs whose parent company is a family business. Design/methodology/approach - Three family companies that have experienced processes supporting the creation of new companies led by family members were used for this exploration. Findings - The findings show that it is possible to form an ecosystem with five basic components from which other factors of a different kind are derived, and that would favour the minimum conditions for new companies to emerge from the family business. Originality/value - Spin-off companies have received valuable recognition in recent years. The vast majority of research on spin-offs considers those arising under the protection of a private innovation centre, a corporation, or university. This research gives more breadth to this coverage, by studying the emergence of spin-offs that rely on the family business as the parent company."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Ecosystem for the emergence of spin-offs from the family business"/>
    <att name="name" value="34"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="ACADEMIA-REVISTA LATINOAMERICANA DE ADMINISTRACION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="42">
    <att name="AB" value="The increasing amount of global waste reflects the social, environmental, and economic trajectories of the local environment. This study addresses this multifaceted problem that requires a holistic view with an ecosystem-level perspective on waste. The research objective is to analyze how the waste business ecosystem enables value capture and creation. Thus, this study contributes to the literature by using a business ecosystem approach that acknowledges several stakeholders, value networks, and the social and environmental issues of the local environment. We qualitatively examine the structure and process of value capture in the waste business ecosystem in two different environments, Finland and Sao Paulo metropolitan area, Brazil. We identify the key stakeholders and their roles, as well as contrast the waste business ecosystem between a developing country and a developed country to unveil differences in value networks. The comparative qualitative case study described relies on the interview and observation of multiple stakeholders. Theoretically, this research builds on the business ecosystem literature, value capture and creation literature, and the extant literature on waste business management As its key result, the study maps two different ecosysteins and their value creation and value capture mechanisms. The findings show that notwithstanding the strong role of regulators in both local environments and their business ecosystems, some private companies engage in value capture. However, the process and structure of the value capture differ in the two case studies. We also found that the stakeholders and their roles in the value capture structure and process vary between these two local environments and with regard to collaboration for value creation. In Finland, ecosystem-level value creation is not rare, but in the Sao Paulo metropolitan area, business models are typically single-firm-centric in terms of value creation and capture. The results presented in this paper delineate and structure the waste business ecosystems in both local environments and provide implications for stakeholders by suggesting the value capture trajectories that can be reached. Finally, fruitful avenues for further research are discussed. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Value capture in business ecosystems for municipal solid waste management: Comparison between two local environments"/>
    <att name="name" value="42"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF CLEANER PRODUCTION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="1"/>
  </node>
  <node id="4">
    <att name="AB" value="Although thereis a rich body of empirical research that uses specific service offerings (e.g. product-related and customer-related services) as proxies for the extent of servitization, the results are inconsistent. We investigate service transitions from an innovation management and resource-based perspective, assessing the service transition stages through the service offering type, service innovativeness and the extent of invested internal and external resources. We use a qualitative approach based on interviews of managers from 19 energy utilities in Germany and complementary longitudinal secondary data. We identify three service transition stages: 1) service initiation, 2) service anchoring and (3) service extension. The findings indicate that firms concurrently experiment with different service offerings and that their services&apos; innovativeness steadily increases during service transition. We contribute to servitization research by identifying barriers in each of the service transition stages that prevent product-centric firms from achieving a higher service transition stage. While in the service initiation stage, firms may face strategy-related barriers, these are often followed by implementation-related barriers in the service anchoring stage and market-related barriers in the service extension stage. To overcome strategy-related barriers, our results indicate that firms should balance their product-oriented and service oriented business model and can benefit from developing a clear strategic intent with relevant service offerings. We further find that implementation-related barriers can be overcome by establishing a service-specific innovation process. To overcome market-related barriers, the findings indicate that firms should integrate customers and external partners in the service innovation ecosystem"/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Service transitions of product-centric firms: An explorative study of service transition stages and barriers in Germany&apos;s energy market"/>
    <att name="name" value="4"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRODUCTION ECONOMICS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="89">
    <att name="AB" value="Entrants in new industries pursue distinct technologies in hopes of winning the technology competition and achieving sustainable competitive advantage. We draw on the complementary assets framework to predict entrants&apos; technology choices in an emerging industry. Evidence from the global solar photovoltaic industry supports our arguments that entrants are more likely to choose technologies with higher technical performance and for which key complementary assets are available in the ecosystem. However, diversifying entrants are more likely to trade off superior performance for complementary asset availability whereas start-up entrants are more likely to trade off complementary asset availability for superior performance. This difference is largely due to diversifying entrants with pre-entry capabilities related to the industry. The study offers a novel illustration of how complementarities and competition shape entry strategies. Copyright (c) 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="COMPLEMENTARITIES AND COMPETITION: UNPACKING THE DRIVERS OF ENTRANTS&apos; TECHNOLOGY CHOICES IN THE SOLAR PHOTOVOLTAIC INDUSTRY"/>
    <att name="name" value="89"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT JOURNAL"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="17"/>
  </node>
  <node id="13">
    <att name="AB" value="There are existing studies that successfully show the impact of corporate social responsibility (CSR) on firms&apos; financial performance. However, limited attention is paid to its impact on the business ecosystem. CSR could be seen as an investment for building a sustainable business ecosystem, which enhances the competitiveness of this system&apos;s members. In that context, this study apprehends and captures the virtuous cycle of firm competitiveness. On analyzing data from interviews with seven firms, the study offers four propositions identifying the structure of the virtuous cycle linking CSR activities to firm competitiveness through the accumulation of social capital within business ecosystems. Based on those propositions, the study offers new insights into CSR research for academics and strategic planning guidelines for managers that integrate social and economic values for a sustainable business ecosystem and firm competitiveness."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Finding the Missing Link between Corporate Social Responsibility and Firm Competitiveness through Social Capital: A Business Ecosystem Perspective"/>
    <att name="name" value="13"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="SUSTAINABILITY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="77">
    <att name="AB" value="A business ecosystem is a community that consists of various levels of interdependent firms which co-evolve in an ongoing cycle and constantly renew themselves. By undertaking an in-depth, qualitative study of multinational companies in the mobile computing industry based in the Great China region, the United Kingdom, and the United States, we explore the nature of the co-evolutionary process and its influence on complex product development. We find that this process consists of three domains of activity: co-vision, co-design, and co-create. We also find that each domain of activity plays a different but important role in stimulating collaborative innovation for complex product development in the mobile computing industry&apos;s business ecosystem. We also discuss the implications for theory and future research directions."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The Nature of the Co-Evolutionary Process: Complex Product Development in the Mobile Computing Industry&apos;s Business Ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="77"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="GROUP &amp; ORGANIZATION MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="3"/>
  </node>
  <node id="133">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper studies how the technological ecosystem extension facilitates the technology substitution in an emerging industry. Specifically, this paper has three findings: 1) the technological ecosystem with an expanded scope including supply, demand and intermediaries; 2) two type of ecosystem extension as the bottom-up and top-down ecosystem extension; 3) the determinants of sustaining the ecosystem extension. We have conducted in-depth interviews in the Chinese low-speed electric vehicle industry, which adopted the bottom-up ecosystem extension by comparing with the traditional car industry with top-down ecosystem extension to the emerging EV industry. This paper also offers managerial implications to the focal firms and policy makers to capture the emerging opportunities within an ecosystem."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Business ecosystem extension: facilitating the technology substitution"/>
    <att name="name" value="133"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2013"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="5"/>
  </node>
  <node id="29">
    <att name="AB" value="The aim of this article is to contribute to a better understanding of the dynamic of business ecosystems (BE) and, more particularly, to identify mechanisms that contribute to their decline. We conduct an historical study of the pinball ecosystem, which experienced steady growth over 60 years and then nearly disappeared. First, it is shown that the pinball case is particularly suitable for the analysis of BE. The major BE characteristics can be identified: a value proposition created by an alignment of partners, the central role played by the platform, the presence of three types of members, and interactions among actors that are based on coopetition. Then, the analysis reveals two factors that explain the decline: keystones&apos; inability to change their business models and their substantial dependence on dominators. The historical perspective also allows us to distinguish certain specific periods in BE decline."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Whatever happened to the &apos;great escape&apos;? Lessons from the rise and decline of the pinball ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="29"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="46">
    <att name="AB" value="Governing a city is arguably one of the most complex management tasks facing organizational leaders. Based on an analysis of Vienna, London, and Chicago, this article demonstrates that city leaders treat cities as ecosystems, structured and governed either as &quot;extended enterprises&quot; where inputs from specialized organizations are coordinated and integrated into the final service or as &quot;platform markets&quot; where direct interactions between third-party service providers and citizens are facilitated by the city leaders. If cities are viewed as the &quot;ecosystem of ecosystems,&quot; then successful city governance requires an orchestration approach where leaders choose the appropriate structure and manage the ecosystem dynamically in a constantly changing environment."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Governing the City: UNLEASHING VALUE FROM THE BUSINESS ECOSYSTEM"/>
    <att name="name" value="46"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="CALIFORNIA MANAGEMENT REVIEW"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="2"/>
  </node>
  <node id="31">
    <att name="AB" value="Purpose - This paper aims to explore the digital economy in the fields of the most promising new technologies: information and communication technologies, biotechnology and nanotechnology. It highlights the convergence of nano-, bio-, info- and cognitive (NBIC) technologies by developing a model for the accurate evaluation of different types of options in the development process of convergent technologies. Design/methodology/approach - The empirical research is based on theoretical analysis and case studies. The authors conducted six in-depth interviews. The study covered different research projects led by centres of excellence, competence centres and institutions that support the transfer of innovations in the economic and business environment. Findings - The research findings prove that there is a convergence of NBIC technologies that can be observed and modelled. The created evolutionary model of NBIC convergence, also based on the theory of real options, allows a proper evaluation of the entire convergence process. Practical implications - For enterprises and scientific research institutions, the NBIC model could represent the starting point for developing further concepts of investment evaluation. The model also considers the indicators of the innovation system, which, in addition to the marketing area, include regulatory challenges of companies ( competition, copyrights, patents, taxation, etc.). Originality/value - This paper enhances the understanding of new technologies in a digital economy. The purpose of this study is to clarify the principal factors for the effective observation and measurement of the convergence phenomenon. It also offers suggestions for improvement of the research and innovation system in the new economy."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Financial evaluation of the convergent technologies development in a digital economy"/>
    <att name="name" value="31"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="KYBERNETES"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="87">
    <att name="AB" value="This study suggests that in the entrepreneurial communities of emerging industries, individual entrepreneurs may simultaneously create opportunities that spill over to others and discover opportunities already created by others. Extant opportunity literature, focused on single actors and their personal networks or on the information function of market prices, is largely mute on the role of opportunities in value networks with distributed entrepreneurial efforts. Ecosystem theory, a literature stream that seldom intersects opportunity literature, contributes with a conceptual framework to study the question. The paper seeks to shed light on how opportunities are created or discovered by new ventures as they are involved in the interlinked endeavor of forming a new ecosystem. The study examines five case studies of US ventures in the early phase of the solar service industry, an industry in which entrepreneurs offer customers access to solar panels as a service rather than as a product. These ventures inadvertently created an industry ecosystem together, as they could not protect the value created by their business partners&apos; new knowledge, or by the emerging social webs between partners. They shaped opportunities together, passing value back and forth amongst themselves. This paper offers fundamental observations on how opportunity creation and discovery is distributed among a community of entrepreneurs as a business ecosystem grows. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Collectively created opportunities in emerging ecosystems: The case of solar service ventures"/>
    <att name="name" value="87"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="15"/>
  </node>
  <node id="188">
    <att name="AB" value="Technical and Scientific Services (TSS) have been largely acknowledged by scholars and policy makers as means of knowledge transfer and difftision within an innovation system. The paper argues that TSS play a critical technology bridging function especially in knowledge-intensive industries, significantly contributing to their development and growth. This issue is investigated through an extensive analysis of the Italian biotech and nanotech industries. The results demonstrate that TSS actually serve as technology bridges along the stages of the technology-intensive industry&apos;s life cycle, connecting sources of technical knowledge (e.g. universities) with recipient organisations (e.g. large private companies), that use the transferred technology to innovate their products or services. The major achievement is that TSS do not play just a brokering function; they perform on the acquired technology value-added activities (i.e. personalisation or recombination) the recipient organisations are willing to pay for, thus ensuring the sustainability of the TSS firm business model."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The knowledge-bridging role of Technical and Scientific Services in knowledge-intensive industries"/>
    <att name="name" value="188"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2008"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="11"/>
  </node>
  <node id="98">
    <att name="AB" value="Policy makers take initiatives to stimulate knowledge ecosystems in technology hotspots. It is implicitly assumed that these ecosystems will lead to value networks through which the participating companies can realize a competitive advantage. Value networks refer to business ecosystems where the value proposition is offered by a group of companies which are mutually complementary. The strategy literature suggests that business ecosystems lead to competitive advantages for each of the partners in the ecosystem. Based on a unique hand-collected database of 138 innovative start-ups in the region of Flanders, we analyze the knowledge and business ecosystem and the financial support network. We find that the knowledge ecosystem is well structured and concentrated around a number of central actors while the business ecosystem is almost non-existent at the local level. Further, we find that the financial support network is almost 100% publicly backed and fails to bridge the knowledge and business ecosystem. The implications for policy makers who tend to focus on the development of local ecosystems are discussed. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Creating value in ecosystems: Crossing the chasm between, knowledge and business ecosystems"/>
    <att name="name" value="98"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="RESEARCH POLICY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="43"/>
  </node>
  <node id="14">
    <att name="AB" value="We study the phenomenon of business ecosystems in which platform firms orchestrate the functioning of ecosystems by providing platforms and setting the rules for participation by complementor firms. We develop a theoretical framework to explain how the structural and evolutionary features of the ecosystem may shape the extent to which participating complementor firms can sustain their superior performance. The structural feature, which we refer to as ecosystem complexity, is a function of the number of unique components or subsystems that interact with the complementor&apos;s product. We incorporate the evolutionary features by considering the role of generational transitions initiated by platform firms over time as well as the role of complementors&apos; ecosystem-specific experience. Evidence from Apple&apos;s iOS and Google&apos;s Android smartphone ecosystems supports our arguments that higher ecosystem complexity helps app developers sustain their superior performance, and that this effect is stronger for more experienced firms. In contrast, platform transitions initiated by Apple and Google make it more difficult for app developers to sustain their performance superiority, and that this effect is exacerbated by the extent of ecosystem complexity. The study offers a novel account of how the performance of complementor firms in platform-based business ecosystems may be shaped by their ecosystem-level interdependencies."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Sustaining Superior Performance in Business Ecosystems: Evidence from Application Software Developers in the iOS and Android Smartphone Ecosystems"/>
    <att name="name" value="14"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="ORGANIZATION SCIENCE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="158">
    <att name="AB" value="Today, the mobile phone industry witnesses important changes, shifting from a value chain to a burgeoning business ecosystem. This paper deals with the relationships that are at the very core of mobile OS ecosystems for IMTs (smartphones and PDA): Microsoft-OS, Symbian-OS, Palm-OS and RIM-OS over the period 1998-2006. Our study confirms that an ecosystem&apos;s borders are unclear. More than half of our sample&apos; relationships are shared by at least two different ecosystems. The ecosystems we studied do not differ in terms of exclusive relationship which suggests that coopetitive strategies are particularly relevant in mobile platforms war. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The borders of mobile handset ecosystems: Is coopetition inevitable?"/>
    <att name="name" value="158"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2011"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TELEMATICS AND INFORMATICS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="15"/>
  </node>
  <node id="187">
    <att name="AB" value="Can the concept of speciation explain evidence on how technologies branch and advance? Can evidence on innovation through spin-off usefully inform the concept of speciation? These questions are addressed through a case study of detailed processes enabling the shift of technology to new domains of application. An innovative IT firm developed its own semiconductor technology to remedy supplier deficiencies but it required a joint venture with a completely new business model to adapt and move the technology into new market domains. We propose the concept of techno-organizational speciation to delineate this phenomenon. Competing perspectives on speciation (compatibility, niche and lineage approaches) are found to illuminate the evidence, while complementarities between these conceptual dimensions are revealed by the case. Causal processes uncovered include the following: (1) Techno-organizational speciation through spin-off may be needed to launch a dominant technical standard, compatible with multiple applications. (2) This can be achieved through niche creation from which develops a new business ecosystem. (3) Inherited knowledge together with organizationally based learning foster the branching and renewal of technological lineages. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Speciation through entrepreneurial spin-off: The Acorn-ARM story"/>
    <att name="name" value="187"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2008"/>
    <att name="SO" value="RESEARCH POLICY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="34"/>
  </node>
  <node id="150">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper explores the effects of entry timing and business model innovation on performance in the early stage of a new product market. Previous research on relationships between entry timing and firm performance has presented conflicting results. Based on a case study of the global MP3 player market, this study examines how entry timing and business model innovation have impacted firms&apos; performances in this new market. A group of market pioneers, including new startups and large early pioneers focusing on hardware-centric product innovations, failed to survive and earn high performance in the new market. In contrast, a late entrant, Apple, with game-changing business model innovations, has dominated the new product market. The business model innovation, which integrated a user-friendly innovative hardware and software platform with the business ecosystem, allows the late entrant to overcome disadvantages from late entry and gain competitive advantages over competitors"/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The effects of entry timing and business model innovation on performance: the case of the global MP3 player market"/>
    <att name="name" value="150"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2011"/>
    <att name="SO" value="ASIAN JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY INNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="2"/>
  </node>
  <node id="47">
    <att name="AB" value="Research summary: Firms introducing disruptive innovations into multisided ecosystems confront the disruptor&apos;s dilemma: gaining the support of the very incumbents they disrupt. Through a longitudinal study of TiVo, a company that pioneered the Digital Video Recorder, we examine how these firms may address this dilemma. Our analysis reveals how TiVo navigated coopetitive tensions by continually adjusting its strategy, its technology platform, and its relational positioning within the evolving U.S. television industry ecosystem. We theorize how (1) disruption may affect not just specific incumbents, but also the entire ecosystem; (2) coopetition is not just dyadic, but also multilateral and intertemporal, and (3) strategy is both a deliberative and emergent process involving continual adjustments, as the disruptor attempts to balance coopetitive tensions over time.Managerial summary: New entrants confront a dilemma when they introduce a disruptive innovation into an existing business ecosystem, viz., how can they gain the support of the incumbents that their innovation disrupts? Confronting this disruptor&apos;s dilemma, the disruptor must consider several issues: How might it pitch its innovation to attract end customers and yet reduce the threat of disruption perceived by ecosystem incumbents? How can the innovation be modified to fit into legacy systems while transforming them? Based on an in-depth analysis of TiVo and its entrepreneurial journey, we explore the strategies disruptors can deploy to address these issues. Copyright (c) 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The disruptor&apos;s dilemma: TiVo and the US television ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="47"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT JOURNAL"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="6"/>
  </node>
  <node id="155">
    <att name="AB" value="In order to define the mobile network operators&apos; strategies of building value network in the 3G era, this paper applies the ecosystem principles to the mobile industry through a China Mobile case study. Based on an analytical framework of such principles, this paper reviews China Mobile&apos;s ecosystem, and identifies its success factors and problems. The results indicate that a complete ecosystem, where mobile network operators collaborate closely with value-added service providers, content/application providers, equipment and device manufacturers, and other involved organizations, can promote the development of mobile data services substantially. Therefore, mobile network operators should play a central role in the ecosystem by managing the entire value-chain and setting up proper value-sharing mechanisms. However, while doing so, problems may arise because of regulatory issues and information asymmetry. High-value common assets, a centralized management system, partner selection schemes and continuous innovations are important success factors. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Business ecosystem strategies of mobile network operators in the 3G era: The case of China Mobile"/>
    <att name="name" value="155"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2011"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TELECOMMUNICATIONS POLICY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="37"/>
  </node>
  <node id="134">
    <att name="AB" value="The aim of this paper is to develop an explicit protocol for gaining the use of new concepts from external and transdisciplinary sources during the theory construction process. We are concerned with Churchman&apos;s sweeping in of alternative perspectives and with inductive research. The potential for innovation that concepts from external disciplines bring is balanced by the risks of working outside a researcher&apos;s area of expertise. There is potential for researcher bias when gathering new ideas as well as when filtering possible new theory, and a protocol might help minimize such problems. For example, few business researchers are fully versed in ecology, and vice versa. This applies to the authors here, but we look at the issue from our respective sides and bring our respective expertise. Hierarchy theory is fundamentally a theory of observation. Here it helps us to define how the perspective of the researcher affects theory construction and the use of transdisciplinary concepts. It introduces a precision about the use of levels and brings out the dualism that arises in movement between levels. We use this to develop a theoretical model of the theory-building process that avoids bias whilst making best use of the researcher&apos;s preconceptions. We illustrate our protocol using the business ecosystem metaphor, which is common in the business literature. Our special case that straddles business and ecology might offer guidance in other transdisciplinary efforts. Copyright (c) 2012 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="A Systematic Consideration of Observational Design Decisions in the Theory Construction Process"/>
    <att name="name" value="134"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2012"/>
    <att name="SO" value="SYSTEMS RESEARCH AND BEHAVIORAL SCIENCE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="2"/>
  </node>
  <node id="61">
    <att name="AB" value="In the face of mounting public environmental and societal concerns, firms are incorporating sustain ability into their business models. However, previous research has paid little attention to how companies can renew their business model to take better account of environmental sustainability at the organizational level in their business ecosystems. This study fills this gap in the literature through a longitudinal case study of the greening of the business model of the US-based carpet manufacturer Interface. The findings delineate the change in the company&apos;s business model, stressing the role of managerial agency in organizational identity formation and in making a favorable change in the ecosystem. Hence, the study examines the links between managerial agency, organizational identity, and business ecosystems with regards to business model greening, and it discusses how shifts in managerial thinking have enabled the company to build the capabilities needed for the change. The article concludes by linking the findings to the body of knowledge on strategic change and providing a new conceptualization of a company&apos;s business model greening. (C) 2015 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd. This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/)."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Environmental sustainability in industrial manufacturing: re-examining the greening of Interface&apos;s business model"/>
    <att name="name" value="61"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF CLEANER PRODUCTION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="2"/>
  </node>
  <node id="126">
    <att name="AB" value="With the growing sophistication and use of information technology, the past decade has witnessed a major growth in financial cybercrime. This paper focuses specifically on credit card fraud and identity theft, examining the globalisation of these activities within a &apos;digital ecosystem&apos; conceptual framework. The relevance of concepts and analytical tools typically used to study legitimate businesses, such as value chains, dynamic capabilities and business models, is explored and tested for their relevance in understanding the scale and nature of illegal activities which are dependant upon innovation and the collective activities of global participants. It is argued that developing a better understanding of how such illegal activities are organised and operate will assist policy makers, law enforcement agencies and security firms to identify trends and concentrate limited resources in a most effective manner. (C) 2012 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The cybercrime ecosystem: Online innovation in the shadows?"/>
    <att name="name" value="126"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2013"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOLOGICAL FORECASTING AND SOCIAL CHANGE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="8"/>
  </node>
  <node id="90">
    <att name="AB" value="The concept of business models and consequently business model innovation has its foundation in corporate practice, strategic management, and industrial economics. However, business models are not a strategy but constitute the core and driver of a strategy as well as the key for decoding, understanding, and effectively communicating a strategy both within an organization as well as across its business ecosystem. As with Business Model, the Business Model Innovation literature is not well developed. This paper focuses on the effects that can be achieved through business model innovation, in particular organizational sustainability. In this regard, the paper focuses on the organizational design and governance and the role different stakeholders, predominantly customers and partners play in the innovation process towards organizational sustainability. Finally, the ways by which organizational performance is influenced by different business models are also explored, aiming to shed light on this theoretical gap. The results provide insights to manufacturers in developing countries, overcoming their dependence on commoditized products and OEM manufacturing while maintaining a sustainable ecosystem. Finally, implications for theory, policy, and practice are outlined along with the suggestions for future research."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Business Model Innovation as Lever of Organizational Sustainability"/>
    <att name="name" value="90"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY TRANSFER"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="21"/>
  </node>
  <node id="0">
    <att name="AB" value="Growing evidence suggests entrepreneurial ecosystems are a potent engine for economic and community development. Prior research has identified an ecosystem&apos;s culture as serving a critical role in its creation and functioning. However, it is not clear how the cultural forces in entrepreneurial ecosystems develop and are shaped by individuals, organizational actors, and ecosystem-level institutions. Drawing from institutional theory and theories of multiple logic organizations (i.e., hybrids), this paper combines entrepreneurship and management research to argue that entrepreneurial ecosystems are influenced by two dominant institutional logics: entrepreneurial-market and community. By combining both logics, hybrid support organizations, such as incubators, accelerators, and small business development centers, play a unique role in entrepreneurial ecosystems by exposing participants to the two guiding logics. Furthermore, it is argued that intra-ecosystem variation among hybrid support organizations in the dominance of entrepreneurial-market and community logics, will result in a diversity of entrepreneurship within an ecosystem. This theorizing contributes to the understanding of entrepreneurial ecosystems by shedding light on the role institutional logics and hybrid support organizations play in ecosystem formation, structuring, and function and by explaining the genesis of the cultural values that guide ecosystem participants."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Hybrid organizations and the logics of entrepreneurial ecosystems"/>
    <att name="name" value="0"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL ENTREPRENEURSHIP AND MANAGEMENT JOURNAL"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="171">
    <att name="AB" value="The paper discusses how organizations call benefit from applying all enhanced Soft Systems Methodology (SSM) in innovation context. The combined approach is illustrated with all intervention in the innovation department of a multinational company. The aim of the company has been to increase its competitiveness by fostering innovation and questioning the innovation system of the company as well as the innovation project portfolio. Embedded in the SSM, the concept of Enterprise Science has been a useful vehicle to structure the problem situation and to channel the search for possible solutions. Innovation challenges could be pointed out, analysed and resolved in a systemic way. Lessons from practice are presented as well as recommendations for decision makers regarding the application of the approach and all outlook to further studies. Copyright (C) 2009 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Embedding Enterprise Science into SSM for Improving Innovation Systems in Technology-Based Companies"/>
    <att name="name" value="171"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2009"/>
    <att name="SO" value="SYSTEMS RESEARCH AND BEHAVIORAL SCIENCE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="2"/>
  </node>
  <node id="138">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper explores how to extract empirical knowledge from R&amp;D, patent, and business literature compilations to help compose an innovation system model. It adapts the key elements and dynamics of technology delivery system modeling to a given Newly Emerging Science &amp; Technology. We present a 10-step analytical approach to help characterize the technology, gauge its state of development, and depict the socio-technical system institutions and actors. We apply this to the case of Dye-Sensitized Solar Cells (DSSCs). A new cross-charting method appears effective at associating novel technology-enabled capabilities to gain functional advantages, and to link those functions to potential applications. The resulting systems model can help private and public sector decision makers grasp key structures and processes, and how these can be tuned to enhance the prospects of successful innovation."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Empirically informing a technology delivery system model for an emerging technology: illustrated for dye-sensitized solar cells"/>
    <att name="name" value="138"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2012"/>
    <att name="SO" value="R &amp; D MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="10"/>
  </node>
  <node id="8">
    <att name="AB" value="The business ecosystem has provided a new paradigm for management research. Most research in the field has focused on profit-driven industries, neglecting the area of the circular economy. This research sets out to capture the mechanisms that the leading firm in the circular economy uses to govern its business ecosystem. The research strategy adopted is a longitudinal case study of the largest glass recycling company in Taiwan, Spring Pool Glass. Our findings illustrate that continuous value capture is the key to governing a sustainable business ecosystem in the glass recycling industry. The mechanisms include continuous value capture to enter new markets, using stakeholder networks to enlarge the business ecosystem, brand image and corporate social responsibility, company capabilities and research and development in the recycling process, and reacting to government policy."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Governing a Sustainable Business Ecosystem in Taiwan&apos;s Circular Economy: The Story of Spring Pool Glass"/>
    <att name="name" value="8"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="SUSTAINABILITY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="38">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper focuses on the strategies of incumbents that seek to develop discontinuous innovations within the boundaries of a mature innovation system. Mature innovation systems do not provide support or these discontinuous innovations. This article focuses Oil exploring why incumbents in these setting engage in discontinuous innovation and what strategies they deploy to become successful. We analyse 10 cases of incumbents developing discontinuous innovations in he mature dutch greenhouse horticulture sector. The results of our analysis show that the incumbents are primarily triggered by dissatisfaction with the current way of doing business and that the existing institutions are the main barrier to discontinuous innovation. In response, the incumbents try to circumvent the existing innovation system in their innovation process, but when successful also engage in changing the existing innovation system. This paper contributes to the understanding of the role of incumbents as source of discontinuous innovation in mature innovation system"/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Innovation at the end of the life cycle: discontinuous innovation strategies by incumbents"/>
    <att name="name" value="38"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INDUSTRY AND INNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="50">
    <att name="AB" value="Publications pushing the &quot;innovation ecosystem&quot; meme have added valuable dimensions to the economic development discussion. The phrase has captured the imagination of policy makers and has motivated public initiatives of substantial magnitude. This paper reviews the concept of innovation ecosystems as it is set forth in the academic and trade literature, and asks, &quot;What is gained from adding &apos;eco-&apos; to our treatment of national and regional innovation systems?&quot; The answer is, &quot;Very little, and the risks outweigh the benefits.&quot; Innovation ecosystem is not yet a clearly defined concept, much less a theory. Moreover, the idea carries pitfalls, notably its over-emphasis on market forces, and its flawed analogy to natural ecosystems. The prospect that the phrase &quot;innovation ecosystem&quot; is here to stay, in investment and economic development circles, implies a research gap, and indicates caution in using the phrase in rigorous research. The paper describes the gap, indicates directions for bridging it, and offers recommendations for prudent use of &quot;ecosystem&quot; terminology. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Innovation ecosystems: A critical examination"/>
    <att name="name" value="50"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="7"/>
  </node>
  <node id="65">
    <att name="AB" value="This research investigates how complex product systems (CoPs)-based innovation ecosystem is created in terms of structure and interactions among players, as well as how technology, value and capability evolve at different stages of an innovation ecosystem. Based on an exploratory case study on the innovation ecosystem of a nuclear power giant-China general nuclear power group (CGN) for the period 1987-2014, this paper presents a framework to explicate the micro-foundation of the formation mechanism of an innovation ecosystem for CoPs. Three ecosystem stages are identified: ecosystem incubation, ecosystem figuration and ecosystem self-renewal. Through the three stages, CGN has been extending its ecosystem gradually from core business to extended network and ecosystem periphery. This study provides theoretical and managerial implications for building and managing innovation ecosystems in developing countries."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Establishing a CoPs-based innovation ecosystem to enhance competence - the case of CGN in China"/>
    <att name="name" value="65"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="62">
    <att name="AB" value="In comparison to the rapid adoption and growth of mobile technologies worldwide, mobile payment services are being adopted at a slower pace than anticipated. One of the interesting characteristics of the Chinese market, for both academicians and practitioners, is that, although m-payment evolved from the convergence of payment and telecommunication industries (traditionally dominated by state-owned enterprises in China), it was private, third party payment companies that developed m-payment platforms, which gained a competitive edge over state-owned enterprises. While standardization, regulation and policy play an important role in stimulating the Chinese m-payment market, these factors alone are not sufficient to establish a sustainable two-sided market and generate a critical mass of merchants and end-users. Although merchants play a crucial role in the m-payment ecosystem, there is a lack of insight into merchant behavior, and their interaction with other actors in the m-payment ecosystem. In this study, we propose a framework for the analyses of the m-payment ecosystem. Starting from a set of propositions, we conducted in-depth interviews to analyze the multifaceted nature of the Chinese m-payment market. We identified the connection between the adoption process and the business ecosystem configurations. The proposed framework can be used as a basis for future studies of complex business ecosystems. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="An analytical framework for an m-payment ecosystem: A merchants&apos; perspective"/>
    <att name="name" value="62"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TELECOMMUNICATIONS POLICY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="3"/>
  </node>
  <node id="66">
    <att name="AB" value="The case of short message service (SMS) Application-to-Person in Norway documents how SMS has re-emerged as a significant channel for customer dialogue: SMS is increasingly used for everything from dentist appointments to communicating with tax authorities. The Technology Innovation Systems perspective is the basis for an assessment of inducement mechanisms for the case, and thus the critical success factors. More specifically, the case serves as an example of a platform-based business ecosystem where the ownership of the platform is shared and a core resource is provided by the mobile network operators. It is shown how the current growth of the SMS channel is founded on collective action in the system, and how the subsequent legitimation process has aligned the SMS channel with user expectations and practices. The actors&apos; ability to collaborate and strike a balance between developing and sharing the market has been critical."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Key success factors for a growing technology innovation system based on SMS Application-to-Person in Norway"/>
    <att name="name" value="66"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOLOGY ANALYSIS &amp; STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="181">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper examines new firms creating innovative networks to support their development in emerging industries. Resource-based and evolutionary theories are combined to explain the genesis of a new business ecosystem. Two case studies of biopharm ventures developing drugs against cancer showed how participants altered their selection environment as they enhanced their network&apos;s capability. Resource building took place at the firm and network level through collaborative business models involving innovative contractors. This approach uncovered previously unnoticed features of networks for drug development: resource asynchronies were found to be a stimulus to innovation in development networks, as in the Penrosean firm."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Combining Resource-Based and Evolutionary Theory to Explain the Genesis of Bio-networks"/>
    <att name="name" value="181"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2008"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INDUSTRY AND INNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="18"/>
  </node>
  <node id="39">
    <att name="AB" value="Introduction: The Electronic Health Records for Clinical Research (EHR4CR) technological platform has been developed to enable the trustworthy reuse of hospital electronic health records data for clinical research. The EHR4CR platform can enhance and speed up clinical research scenarios: protocol feasibility assessment, patient identification for recruitment in clinical trials, and clinical data exchange, including for reporting serious adverse events. Our objective was to seed a multi-stakeholder ecosystem to enable the scalable exploitation of the EHR4CR platform in Europe, and to assess its economic sustainability. Materials and methods: Market analyses were conducted by a multidisciplinary task force to define an EHR4CR emerging ecosystem and multi-stakeholder value chain. This involved mapping stakeholder groups and defining their unmet needs, incentives, potential barriers for adopting innovative solutions, roles and interdependencies. A comprehensive business model, value propositions, and sustainability strategies were developed accordingly. Using simulation modelling (including Monte Carlo simulations) and a 5-year horizon, the potential financial outcomes of the business model were forecasted from the perspective of an EHR4CR service provider. Results: A business ecosystem was defined to leverage the EHR4CR multi-stakeholder value chain. Value propositions were developed describing the expected benefits of EHR4CR solutions for all stakeholders. From an EHR4CR service provider&apos;s viewpoint, the business model simulation estimated that a profitability ratio of up to 1.8 could be achieved at year 1, with potential for growth in subsequent years depending on projected market uptake. Conclusions: By enhancing and speeding up existing processes, EHR4CR solutions promise to transform the clinical research landscape. The ecosystem defined provides the organisational framework for optimising the value and benefits for all stakeholders involved, in a sustainable manner. Our study suggests that the exploitation of EHR4CR solutions appears profitable and sustainable in Europe, with a growth potential depending on the rates of market and hospital adoption. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ireland Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Business analysis for a sustainable, multi-stakeholder ecosystem for leveraging the Electronic Health Records for Clinical Research (EHR4CR) platform in Europe"/>
    <att name="name" value="39"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MEDICAL INFORMATICS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="1"/>
  </node>
  <node id="108">
    <att name="AB" value="Initially hailed as a miracle crop for biofuel production, Jatropha has recently attracted criticism for competing with food production, causing adverse biodiversity impacts, and jeopardizing land access by rural populations in tropical countries. This article analyzes the contested development of Jatropha biofuel sector in Tanzania by anchoring two new concepts of &quot;organizational models&quot; and &quot;institutional arrangements&quot; to the sectoral systems of innovation perspective. The notion of &quot;organizational models&quot; brings into relief the heterogeneity of actors in an innovation system and the ways in which the actors form networks, within and across national borders, to organize innovative activities. The concept of &quot;institutional arrangements&quot; refers to the ensemble of formal and informal institutions assembled during Tanzania&apos;s colonial and postcolonial eras, which directly govern innovative activities in specific organizational models. Based on a location-specific and historically grounded institutional analysis within the innovation system framework, implications are drawn for the future development of Tanzania&apos;s Jatropha sector including its links with European markets and for the regulation of &quot;next-generation&quot; biofuels."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Governed by history: institutional analysis of a contested biofuel innovation system in Tanzania"/>
    <att name="name" value="108"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INDUSTRIAL AND CORPORATE CHANGE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="1"/>
  </node>
  <node id="81">
    <att name="AB" value="Strategic and industrial analysis reveals it is extremely difficult to enter a market dominated by an existing platform. In fact, direct or indirect network effects give the established company&apos;s platform a considerable competitive edge. This is true of the numerical computation market and the Matlab + Simulink platform by MathWorks. The case study of Scilab Enterprises helps identify conditions of viability for breaking into such a market. We find that alone, the platform strategy is doomed to fail, but accompanied by an open strategy, entering a platform market becomes possible. We hypothesize that a platform strategy is successful when associated with an open innovation process (integration of the open source community) and supported by a business ecosystem (a huge community of developers, users, and allies). Copyright (c) 2015 ASAC. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Resume L&apos;analyse strategique et industrielle montre qu&apos;il est extremement difficile, pour un nouvel entrant, de penetrer un marche domine par une plateforme en place. C&apos;est le cas du marche du calcul numerique avec la plateforme Matlab + Simulink de MathWorks. L&apos;etude de cas de Scilab Enterprises permet, dans ce contexte particulier, d&apos;identifier des conditions de viabilite d&apos;une strategie d&apos;entree sur un tel marche. En soi, la strategie de plateforme seule est vouee a l&apos;echec. Accompagnee d&apos;une strategie ouverte, cette entree devient possible. La strategie ouverte est definie ici comme une strategie de plateforme associee a un processus d&apos;innovation ouverte (integration de la communaute open source) et s&apos;appuyant sur un vaste ecosysteme d&apos;affaires (vaste communaute de developpeurs, d&apos;utilisateurs et d&apos;allies). Copyright (c) 2015 ASAC. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Entrance into a platform-dominated market: Virtue of an open strategy on the numerical computation market"/>
    <att name="name" value="81"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="CANADIAN JOURNAL OF ADMINISTRATIVE SCIENCES-REVUE CANADIENNE DES SCIENCES DE L ADMINISTRATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="106">
    <att name="AB" value="Planning new product development (NPD) activities is becoming increasingly difficult, as contemporary businesses compete at the level of business ecosystems in addition to the firm-level product-market competition. These business ecosystems are built around platforms interlinking suppliers, complementors, distributors, developers, etc. together. The competitiveness of these ecosystems relies on members utilizing the shared platform for their own performance improvement, especially in terms of developing new valuable offerings for end users. Therefore, managing the development of the platform-based applications and gaining timely end-user input for NPD are of vital importance both to the ecosystem as a whole and to the developers. Subsequently, to succeed in NPD planning developers utilizing beta testing need a thorough understanding of the adoption dynamics of beta products. Developers need to plan for example resource allocation; development costs; and timing of commercial, end-product launches. Therefore, the anticipation of the adoption dynamics of beta products emerges as an important antecedent in planning NPD activities when beta testing is used for gaining end-user input to the NPD process. Consequently, we investigate how free beta software products that are built upon software platforms diffuse among their end users in a cocreation community. We specifically study whether the adoption of these beta products follows Bass or Gompertz model dynamics used in the previous literature when modeling the adoption of stand-alone products. Further, we also investigate the forecasting abilities of these two models. Our results show that the adoption dynamics of free beta products in a cocreation community follow Gompertz&apos;s model rather than the Bass model. Additionally, we find that the Gompertz model performs better than the Bass model in forecasting both short and long out-of-sample time periods. We further discuss the managerial and research implications of our study."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Investigating Adoption of Free Beta Applications in a Platform-Based Business Ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="106"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF PRODUCT INNOVATION MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="7"/>
  </node>
  <node id="25">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper investigates opportunities to enhance Future-oriented Technology Analysis (FTA) of emerging technologies within innovation systems. We address key challenges faced by policymakers developing innovation strategies for emerging technologies. In particular, we explore ways that FM might be structured to investigate the complex innovation system journeys of novel technologies as they are developed, diffused, and deployed. In doing this, we draw on concepts from technology and operations management and related literatures to more carefully characterise the: (1) &apos;technical infrastrucutre&apos; required to develop emerging technologies; (2) key technology transitions involved in diffusion; and (3) complex industrial value networks into which they may eventually get deployed. We investigate the extent to which these categories are already used within national technology foresight exercises. In particular, we review over 240 international FTA-related policy, strategy, and analysis documents for &apos;advanced materials&apos;. We find that - although generally used inconsistently and unsystematically within FTA - these categories repeatedly emerge as important elements in many policies, strategies, and underpinning foresight exercises. We conclude by arguing that these categories should be carefully considered in initial FTA design. And that, by doing so, FTA exercises may better reveal potential &apos;innovation system failures&apos; and help policymakers coordinate policy actions in response. (C) 2016 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Enabling technologies, lifecycle transitions, and industrial systems in technology foresight: Insights from advanced materials FTA"/>
    <att name="name" value="25"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOLOGICAL FORECASTING AND SOCIAL CHANGE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="1"/>
  </node>
  <node id="136">
    <att name="AB" value="Success in business ecosystems that include well-established companies and new ventures requires collaboration and competition, a task that demands strategic thinking to leverage a firm&apos;s resources and capabilities. Strategic thinking and the entrepreneurial activities in an ecosystem influence one another in a cycle that perpetuates and even sparks innovation. These interactions vary significantly across four types of business ecosystems-Orchestra, Creative Bazaar, Jam Central, and MOD Station-and determine the success and failures of new ventures and established companies. The nature and effect of the dynamic interactions in a business ecosystem can have profound implications for organizational success. (C) 2011 Kelley School of Business, Indiana University. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Entrepreneurship and strategic thinking in business ecosystems"/>
    <att name="name" value="136"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2012"/>
    <att name="SO" value="BUSINESS HORIZONS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="39"/>
  </node>
  <node id="45">
    <att name="AB" value="This study aims to analyze the fuzzy front end stage (FFE) of systemic innovations, which are characterised by interdependence with other innovations and actors of the business ecosystem. The methodological approach selected is a systematic literature review based on bibliometric, social network analysis and content analysis. The analysis of the literature reveals that systemic innovations are addressed in a limited manner in specialised articles on FFE. The main frameworks on FFE were analysed in-depth and a conceptual framework for the fuzzy front-end stage of systemic innovations was proposed, encompassing the following elements: (i) ecosystem mapping and identification of the organisation positioning within the ecosystem during the analysis of the influence factors; (ii) use of mechanisms of coordination, collaboration, self-regulation and adaptation as innovation drivers; (iii) conception of new business models, value networks or strategic positioning as a result of the definition of concepts; and (iv) strategic planning or corporate venture capital as stages subsequent to the FFE, instead of the formal process of new product development. (C) 2016 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Fuzzy front end of systemic innovations: A conceptual framework based on a systematic literature review"/>
    <att name="name" value="45"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOLOGICAL FORECASTING AND SOCIAL CHANGE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="118">
    <att name="AB" value="The US national innovation system has a dual structure: part suited to rapid innovation, and part stubbornly resistant to change. The complex, established Legacy sectors&apos; that resist change, particularly disruptive innovation, share common features that obstruct the market launch of innovations, over and above the valley of death&apos; and other obstacles that have been the traditional focus of innovation policy. Innovations in Legacy sectors must penetrate a well-established and well-defended technological/economic/political/social paradigm that favours existing technology, characterised by (1) perverse&apos; subsidies and price structures that create a mismatch between the incentives of producers and broader social goals, such as environmental sustainability, public health and safety, and geopolitical security; (2) established infrastructure and institutional architecture that imposes regulatory hurdles or other disadvantages to new entrants (3) market imperfections beyond those faced by other innovations: network economies, lumpiness, economies of scale, split incentives, needs for collective action, and transaction costs (4) politically powerful vested interests, reinforced by public support, that defend the paradigm and resist innovations that threaten their business models (5) public habits and expectations attuned to existing technology and (6) an established knowledge and human resources structure adapted to its needs. Beyond these obstacles, more socially desirable technologies that are driven by environmental or other non-market considerations must overcome the lack of agreed replacement standards against which putative alternatives can be judged. We have developed a new, integrative analytic framework for categorising the obstacles to market launch faced by Legacy sectors, and earlier applied this method to energy, health delivery, the long-distance electric grid, building, and air transport. In energy especially, the requirement for innovation is sufficiently urgent that large-scale domestic and collaborative international research should take place even at the cost of possible competitive disadvantage and even if it is some time before the USA adopts carbon charges and thereby puts pressure on the prevailing paradigm of fossil fuel use. We now extend this method to sustainable agriculture. American paradigms in agriculture and in energy are exported worldwide, delaying the development and spread of needed innovations that are not consistent with them. Foreign manufacturers wishing to enter US markets must suit their products in these sectors to American paradigms, while American exports of technology may be insufficiently cost conscious or respectful of environmental sustainability. Developing countries are technology takers and suffer from asymmetric innovative capability. They need to choose sources of technology best suited to their situation. India and China constitute new competitive threats, but also represent innovative developing countries&apos; that have large domestic markets in which they are launching innovations aimed at their lower income populations."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Legacy sectors: barriers to global innovation in agriculture and energy"/>
    <att name="name" value="118"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2013"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOLOGY ANALYSIS &amp; STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="4"/>
  </node>
  <node id="28">
    <att name="AB" value="In this paper, we focus on how focal firms influence business ecosystem stability through patent management. We present and discuss a case study of Thales Alenia Space, a leader in the aerospace industry, and its ecosystem partners. We make two counterintuitive insights about ecosystem management. First, a focal firm can use patents in a new way in order to ensure the stability of its ecosystem. Second, patent licensing facilitates an inverted pattern of knowledge creation and commercialisation between large and small firms, in which small firms are able to commercialise innovations created by large firms in unexpected markets. Furthermore, this article contributes to the literature on patent management by providing new evidence on the external leveraging of knowledge."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Using patents to orchestrate ecosystem stability: the case of a French aerospace company"/>
    <att name="name" value="28"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="109">
    <att name="AB" value="The aim of this article is to contribute to literature with new findings from biogenetics that are becoming increasingly important. In particular, we will discuss the new analytic frameworks that may open as a result of the incorporation of epigenetics in evolutionary economic thinking. This new approach is illustrated by studying the evolution of big Internet industry groups such as Apple, Google, Microsoft, Facebook, Amazon and Samsung. With it we shed light on the dynamics of business groups, which we approach as &apos;business ecosystems&apos;. We introduce the concept of Epigenetic Economic Dynamics, which is defined as the study of the epigenetic dynamics generated as a result of the adaptation of organisations to major changes in their respective environments. First of all, this concept enables us to understand how the dynamics of the business groups mentioned address changes in their environments. Secondly, it is also useful when analysing the results of these dynamics. Abnormalities, malfunctions or obstacles to innovation, and/or blockage to developing competition at certain levels (i.e. intellectual property rights, abuse of monopoly power, etc.) may arise as a result of the influence of epigenetic dynamics. Acquisition of patent portfolios and patent lawsuits for infringements and violations are quite common, for example in the field of mobile telephony, which clearly shows the fierce competition between business groups. Essential patents licensing is particularly at the core of legal disputes between the business groups. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Epigenetic Economic Dynamics: The evolution of big internet business ecosystems, evidence for patents"/>
    <att name="name" value="109"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="8"/>
  </node>
  <node id="55">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper analyses the diversity of goals and values amongst 26 Brazilian commercial-scale beef farmers previously identified as exhibiting progressive technology adoption behaviours, and considers the implications for the agricultural innovation system (AIS). Following the Q-methodology guidelines, four main sets of goals and values were identified and labelled: the Professional Farmer (PF), the Committed Environmentalist (CE), the Profit Maximiser (PM) and the Aspirant Top Farmer (ATF). All farmer types believed in operating the farm as a business and agreed with the notion that cattle production and nature conservation are compatible. The PF aimed to run the farm professionally, based on sound technical and managerial practices. The CE put a particularly strong emphasis on the long-term sustainability of the farming system. The PM focused on technical issues to pursue economic returns and efficiency, thereby also creating space for lifestyle objectives. The ATF sought physical farm and livestock excellence, was growth oriented, and sought recognition by peers. These four typologies have implications for the farmers&apos; technology adoption and its promotion, e.g. they are likely to influence the uptake of particular types of innovations, and reinforce the importance of considering AIS within a social systems framework. This is the first Q-methodology study to demonstrate considerable diversity of values and goals within a subset of technology-adopting progressive farmers, with implications within agricultural innovation systems for the integration of goal diversity and adoption theory. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Assessing the diversity of values and goals amongst Brazilian commercial-scale progressive beef farmers using Q-methodology"/>
    <att name="name" value="55"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="AGRICULTURAL SYSTEMS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="3"/>
  </node>
  <node id="103">
    <att name="AB" value="How does technological innovation fit with business model design to jointly impact firm growth? Given the increasingly salient role of business model, extant literature provides little answer to this question. This study builds a theoretical model based on technological innovation literature, business ecosystem theory, and business model literature to investigate this issue. This study finds that exploitative innovation and exploratory innovation fit with different business model designs to promote firm growth. Six hypotheses are proposed and examined by a database from 176 Chinese firms. This research finds that exploitative innovation has a negative whereas exploratory innovation has a positive effect on firm growth. More importantly, we find that efficiency-centered business model design enhances the negative effect of exploitative innovation and weakens the positive effect of exploratory innovation. We also find that novelty-centered business model design weakens the negative effect of exploitative innovation. This research contributes to both technological innovation and business model design literature."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The fit between technological innovation and business model design for firm growth: evidence from China"/>
    <att name="name" value="103"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="R &amp; D MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="12"/>
  </node>
  <node id="49">
    <att name="AB" value="Research summary: The study explores renewal in a novel but understudied contextan era of ferment with competing technological options. It focuses on IBM&apos;s transition from market leadership in a failed path (plasma) to leadership in the emerging dominant technology (LCD) in the 1980s. Interviews and internal documents offer two primary factors explaining renewal at IBM. First, IBM Research had a hybrid structure that captured the benefits of both centralized and decentralized R&amp;D. Second, middle managers shaped senior management cognitive frames to focus on business-related issues instead of specific technical issues, thus bypassing biases often resulting from failure. The study offers an integrated framework on what facilitates flexibility at the technology, organization, and decision-making levels. This flexibility helps firms survive a turbulent era of ferment.Managerial summary: Firms facing technological uncertainty may need to recover from unlucky bets. But responding to failure is politically and organizationally difficult. This study explores how IBM recovered from its failed bet on plasma displays to lead the LCD display market. This study identifies six key factors, highlighting two. First, IBM&apos;s researchers received centralized funding, but could also receive funding directly from division managers. This structure helped preserve options and variety. Second, internal LCD champions focused on the business case for displays and not technology. This fostered technology agnosticism and helped avoid managerial biases from failure. For managers looking to use real options to maintain flexibility in an uncertain environment, this study offers clear suggestions related to design and decision making that can foster flexibility. Copyright (c) 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Reversing course: Competing technologies, mistakes, and renewal in flat panel displays"/>
    <att name="name" value="49"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT JOURNAL"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="2"/>
  </node>
  <node id="5">
    <att name="AB" value="The paper develops the structure of business ecosystems, operating mechanisms and integrated configuration models by examining multiple case studies of electric vehicle (EV) producers in China and the EU (Germany, France and Denmark). The EV ecosystem can be categorized into four paradigms using a target market (mainstream or niche innovation) and growth context (advanced economies or emerging economies). These four paradigms are advanced mainstream, advanced niche, emerging mainstream and emerging niche. This research also explores three key operating mechanisms with which to organize EV business ecosystems, namely vision developing, platform organizing and institution re-configuring. As a latecomer,compared with western paradigms, the development of Chinese EV industry is more openly engaged with vision development, platform organization and institution reconfiguration, such as government regulation."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Organizing business ecosystems in emerging electric vehicle industry: Structure, mechanism, and integrated configuration"/>
    <att name="name" value="5"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="ENERGY POLICY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="3">
    <att name="AB" value="Identifying the trends and features of metaknowledge will help scholars track knowledge through topics. This paper designs a new methodology to make it in a certain field. The proposed novel design performs well in the interdisciplinary domain where there are plenty noisy data and conflicting findings. This study applies this research design to a typical interdisciplinary domain, i.e. innovation and entrepreneurial ecosystems. To identify the scope of research and rationalize data collection process, this paper makes a definition of innovation and entrepreneurial ecosystems based on previous researches. Next, we design two data filtering procedures, which can handle the noisy data and provide the datasets for sequence analyses. Then, we adopt the co-citation analysis and network meta-analysis to clarify the trends and features of multiple metaknowledges. Finally, we draw conclusions about emerging trends, mainstream and hotspots, current situation, future challenges or other features of metaknowledge. We also integrate some conflicting findings, which provide more accurate evidences for the field. Evidences show that this novel research design is an effective tool for analyzing metaknowledges and also suitable for other fields."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="How to identify metaknowledge trends and features in a certain research field? Evidences from innovation and entrepreneurial ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="3"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="SCIENTOMETRICS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="64">
    <att name="AB" value="The main objective of this study is to identify which knowledge flows are key elements for designing an inter-organisational technological platform. It mobilises the literature of platform strategies and the architectural innovation theory. In the literature, the technological platform already exists, is the property of only one firm, and is the starting point for an inter-organisational innovation process because it is enhanced and enriched by niche players. This paper considers the case of a digital business ecosystem where the technological platform does not already exist and is co-designed. We study the design process of an inter organisational technological platform and, more specifically, its emergence, its development, and its potential evolution. The aim is to know how and under which conditions and with what objective an emerging technological platform is fundamental to the analysis of the emergence of the business ecosystem and the strategic positioning of each member."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Architectural knowledge: key flows and processes in designing an inter-organisational technological platform"/>
    <att name="name" value="64"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="KNOWLEDGE MANAGEMENT RESEARCH &amp; PRACTICE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="101">
    <att name="AB" value="Technology platform strategies offer a novel way to orchestrate a rich portfolio of contributions made by the many independent actors who form an ecosystem of heterogeneous complementors around a stable platform core. This form of organising has been successfully used in smartphone, gaming, commercial software, and industrial sectors. Technology ecosystems require stability and homogeneity to leverage common investments in standard components, but they also need variability and heterogeneity to meet evolving market demand. Although the required balance between stability and evolvability in the ecosystem has been addressed conceptually in the literature, we have less understanding of its underlying mechanics or appropriate governance. Through an extensive case study of a business software ecosystem consisting of a major multinational manufacturer of enterprise resource planning software at the core and a heterogeneous system of independent implementation partners and solution developers on the periphery, our research identifies three salient tensions that characterize the ecosystem: standard-variety, control-autonomy, and collective-individual. We then highlight the specific ecosystem governance mechanisms designed to simultaneously manage desirable and undesirable variance across each tension. Paradoxical tensions may manifest as dualities, where tensions are framed as complementary and mutually enabling. Alternatively, they may manifest as dualisms, where actors are faced with contradictory and disabling &quot;either ... or&quot; decisions. We identify conditions where latent, complementary tensions become manifest as salient, contradictory tensions. By identifying conditions in which complementary logics are overshadowed by contradictory logics, our study further contributes to the understanding of the dynamics of technology ecosystems, as well as the effective design of technology ecosystem governance that can explicitly embrace paradoxical tensions toward generative outcomes."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Technology Ecosystem Governance"/>
    <att name="name" value="101"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="ORGANIZATION SCIENCE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="29"/>
  </node>
  <node id="97">
    <att name="AB" value="At present, governments are embarking on the ambitious undertaking of increasing their countries&apos; market share of renewable energy. Political ambitions, however, are just one of the driving forces for energy companies&apos; to engage in innovative climate projects. Energy companies&apos; perceptions of business opportunities are dependent on a set of factors that influence their innovation ambitions. This research operationalizes previous work on the main drivers of the establishment of Renewable Energy Technologies (RETs), with the aim of presenting an overview of the typical systemic drivers within a technological innovation system (TIS) framework. This leads to the proposal of a comprehensive typology and categorization of drivers of RETs. The typology is validated empirically by analyzing data on the development of four types of RETs (wind, solar, biomass and wave energy) in eight European countries (EU-7 and Ireland). The study&apos;s results shed light on the multilateral drivers behind the development of RETs. Furthermore, a cross-case comparative study reveals the differences between drivers of RETs and the patterns of these drivers in different countries. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="What drives the development of renewable energy technologies? Toward a typology for the systemic drivers"/>
    <att name="name" value="97"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="RENEWABLE &amp; SUSTAINABLE ENERGY REVIEWS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="14"/>
  </node>
  <node id="15">
    <att name="AB" value="Information services based on the Internet of Things (IoT) help to integrate information and material flows and to optimize supply chain management (SCM). However, the design, implementation and operation of such services require strong cooperations between different types of company. Firms that are actively involved in SCM, such as logistics service providers, have to set up their own ecosystem in order to realize and run such services. Following this line of thinking, the aim of this paper is to support logistics companies with recommendations for the design of their own IoT ecosystem and the realization of IoT services. The grounded theory methodology is used to develop a theoretical IoT ecosystem model. A model with 19 different roles, their relationships and value contributions emerged during the research process. Our findings help companies to understand the implementation of IoT services, to find the right partners with which to cooperate, and to establish their own ecosystem."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Development of an Ecosystem Model for the Realization of Internet of Things (IoT) Services in Supply Chain Management"/>
    <att name="name" value="15"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="ELECTRONIC MARKETS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="110">
    <att name="AB" value="New service development (NSD) is the process of creating new services to fulfill target customers&apos; needs. It is essential that an NSD project team cooperate across organizational boundaries and various disciplines to achieve the sustainability goal of an NSD project. This study adopted Activity Theory to understand dynamics of complex service innovation system and model the actions taken by different entities in telehealth service projects, in which we identified important contradictions that affect the sustainability of newly developed services. Based on multiple case study findings, this research identified challenges for these new service development projects such as user needs identification, the involvement of emergent technology and collaboration between entities from different industries. This study contributes to the NSD research by proposing five propositions which could be used for guiding stakeholders to effectively manage NSD projects to offer sustainable newly developed services. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Analyzing the sustainability of a newly developed service: An activity theory perspective"/>
    <att name="name" value="110"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="6"/>
  </node>
  <node id="72">
    <att name="AB" value="The growth of regional ports (in sub-national context) and their host regions is conditional upon one another. A regional port requires a vision for growing its business as well as its region. To achieve this goal, it is essential for regional ports to initiate effective strategies. This paper explores the pertinent factors and strategic initiatives for effective involvement of Australian regional ports in regional development through a questionnaire survey to Australian regional port stakeholders. Using exploratory and confirmatory factor analyses, this study suggests that Australian regional ports undertake multiple strategies when involved in regional development, including collaboration to create supply chain efficiency, collaboration with regional organisations for regional growth, playing a proactive role in the regional innovation system, and being pro-active for port&apos;s environmental and social responsibility."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Investigating the strategies for Australian regional ports&apos; involvement in regional development"/>
    <att name="name" value="72"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF SHIPPING AND TRANSPORT LOGISTICS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="176">
    <att name="AB" value="A business ecosystem provides a new perspective for repositioning a company&apos;s strategy in order to aggressively further its own interests and to promote its overall ecosystem health. Analyzing a business ecosystem is not an easy task, and therefore only a few studies have been made, even though some scholars and managers accept this concept from ecology since value creation is achieved by establishing a platform that other members of the ecosystem can use to enhance their performance. This paper presents a case study based on both qualitative and quantitative data, by explaining how Cisco Systems has been so successful in utilizing its strategy of mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;A) for corporate growth based on a business ecosystem, especially from a technological perspective. We use US patent data from 1993 to 2005 to illustrate Cisco&apos;s technological roadmap. Finally, implications of symbiosis, platform, and co-evolution are provided for managers to challenge the contemporary business environment. (C) 2009 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The technological roadmap of Cisco&apos;s business ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="176"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2009"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="64"/>
  </node>
  <node id="96">
    <att name="AB" value="For more than a decade, the Smart Home has promised to offer a better quality of life by connecting in-house devices and monitoring their usage. Such platform-based configurational technology has demonstrated the potential to improve comfort, healthcare, safety and security, and energy conservation both at home and in the office. Moreover, since these technologies foster users&apos; independence, Smart Homes can be both an answer to an aging workforce and a large market for an aging customer base. Nonetheless, so far market adoption has mostly been limited to the luxury segment and the more basic stand-alone technologies. Therefore, the main question driving this study is why Smart Home technology is so scarcely implemented despite its benefits to an aging population. From the literature we derive key market barriers in Smart Home value networks. We expand on these findings by means of a value network analysis of a Dutch smart home implementation case. In addition, we conducted 14 interviews that provide more insight into the value network of specific Smart Home services. Based on our case findings we develop a generic value network for Smart Homes and propose opportunities to improve market adoption of Smart Home technologies. (C) 2014 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Market adoption barriers of multi-stakeholder technology: Smart homes for the aging population"/>
    <att name="name" value="96"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOLOGICAL FORECASTING AND SOCIAL CHANGE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="9"/>
  </node>
  <node id="80">
    <att name="AB" value="The past twenty years have been a time of many new technological developments, changing business practices, and interesting innovations in the financial information system (IS) and technology landscape. They have led to the increasing use of prior innovations that have supported e-commerce, and that are now being brought into financial services to support different kinds of improvements to core business processes. This research examines recent changes in the payment sector in financial services, specifically related to mobile payments (m-payments) that enable new channels for consumer payments for goods and services purchases, and other forms of economic exchange. We extend recent research on technology ecosystems and paths of influence analysis for how industry-centered technology innovations arise and evolve. We explore the extent to which they can be understood through the lens of several simple building blocks, including technology components, technology-based services, and the technology-supported infrastructures that provide foundations for the related digital businesses. Our extension of the prior research focuses on two key elements: (1) modeling the impacts of competition and cooperation on different forms of innovations in the aforementioned building blocks; and (2) representing the role that regulatory forces play in driving or delaying innovation in the larger scope of our modeling approach. To assess the efficacy of our approach, we use it to retrospectively analyze the past two decades of innovations in the m-payments space. Our results identify the industry-specific patterns of innovation that have occurred, suggest how they have been affected by competition, cooperation and regulation, and point out some more universal patterns of technology innovations that offer insights into the development of e-commerce. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Competition, cooperation, and regulation: Understanding the evolution of the mobile payments technology ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="80"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="ELECTRONIC COMMERCE RESEARCH AND APPLICATIONS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="7"/>
  </node>
  <node id="27">
    <att name="AB" value="We investigate how a set of small and medium sized enterprises (SMEs) can engage in business model development within a regional innovation ecosystem. Based on a case of Danish manufacturing SMEs that developed their local ecosystem in an innovative automation project, we find key drivers and challenges that these companies encountered while creating and capturing value both for them and the ecosystem at large. While the value creation process is enabled by common goals and financial support, companies need to balance their core activities with their commitment to the joint initiative. Moreover, ecosystem development is centrally dependent on the value-capture process, which also takes place at the inter-organisational level. Such open innovation process implies a purposive management of knowledge flows at the level of the innovation ecosystem that fits a multi-layered structure of the business model. Our findings also highlight the underlying connection between the business model and ecosystem concepts."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Creating and capturing value in a regional innovation ecosystem: a study of how manufacturing SMEs develop collaborative solutions"/>
    <att name="name" value="27"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="164">
    <att name="AB" value="The success of an innovating firm often depends on the efforts of other innovators in its environment. How do the challenges faced by external innovators affect the focal firm&apos;s outcomes? To address this question we first characterize the external environment according to the structure Of interdependence. We follow the flow of inputs and outputs in the ecosystem to distinguish between upstream components that tire handled by the focal firm, and downstream complements that are bundled by the firm&apos;s customers. We hypothesize that the effects of external innovation challenges depend not only on their magnitude, but also 017 their location in the ecosystem relative to the focal firm. We identify a key asymmetry that results from the location of challenges relative to a focal firm-greater upstream innovation challenges in components enhance the benefits that accrue to technology leaders, while greater downstream innovation challenges in complements erode these benefits. We,further propose that the effectiveness of vertical integration as a strategy to manage ecosystem interdependence increases over the course of the technology life cycle. Me explore these arguments in the context of the global semiconductor lithography equipment industry from its emergence in 1962 to 2005 across nine distinct technology generations. We find strong empirical support for our framework. Copyright (C) 2009 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="VALUE CREATION IN INNOVATION ECOSYSTEMS: HOW THE STRUCTURE OF TECHNOLOGICAL INTERDEPENDENCE AFFECTS FIRM PERFORMANCE IN NEW TECHNOLOGY GENERATIONS"/>
    <att name="name" value="164"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2010"/>
    <att name="SO" value="STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT JOURNAL"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="292"/>
  </node>
  <node id="122">
    <att name="AB" value="Sustainable strategic management emerged from the coevolution of strategic thinking in today&apos;s sustainability challenging business environment. Business ecosystems, designed to create socially and ecologically responsible economic opportunities for their members, have emerged as excellent structures for implementing sustainable strategic management strategies along the whole pyramid of coevolving developed, developing, and undeveloped markets. Both the business ecosystem leaders and niche players in these whole pyramid business ecosystems have critical roles to play in formulating and implementing potentially profitable strategies that help reduce the human footprint and improve the quality of human life. Ecosystem leaders need to be responsible for creating and shepherding their business ecosystems&apos; visions of a sustainable future, and niche players need to be responsible for providing the ecosystem with an innovation trajectory designed to make those visions a reality."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The Coevolution of Sustainable Strategic Management in the Global Marketplace"/>
    <att name="name" value="122"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2013"/>
    <att name="SO" value="ORGANIZATION &amp; ENVIRONMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="11"/>
  </node>
  <node id="79">
    <att name="AB" value="Technology-based financial innovations over the past four decades have led to transformations in the financial markets. Understanding technological innovations in financial information systems (IS) and technologies has been challenging for technology consultants and financial industry practitioners due to the underlying complexities though. In this article, we propose an ecosystem analysis approach by extending the technology ecosystem paths of influence model (Adomavicius et al., 2008a) to incorporate stakeholder actions, considering both supply-side and demand-side forces for technological change. Our ecosystem model brings together three original core elements: technology components, technology-based services, and technology-supported business infrastructures. We also contribute a fourth new element to this approach involving stakeholder analysis. We investigate innovations in the area of high-frequency trading (HFT) technologies as a basis for empirically validating the existence of several different patterns in the historical path of technology evolution. Our analysis results suggest that supply-side and demand-side forces influenced HFT technology innovations and contributed to changes in the financial markets. This research represents some of the first work that investigates financial market technology innovations at the technology and stakeholder levels. It also offers a useful and practical tool to help managers and analysts to understand the nature of technology-based financial innovations and the relationships between technology and financial markets that support their emergence. (C) 2014 Elsevier Inc All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Innovations in financial IS and technology ecosystems: High-frequency trading in the equity market"/>
    <att name="name" value="79"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOLOGICAL FORECASTING AND SOCIAL CHANGE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="1"/>
  </node>
  <node id="67">
    <att name="AB" value="Purpose - Increasing competition in global markets requires many countries to seek new growth sectors. In addition, the nature of competition is changing. This paper applies the business ecosystem concept and studies San Diego as a spatial health and life sciences ecosystem. The purpose of this paper is to identify issues that should be considered in design of innovation policies and regional industry development. Design/methodology/approach - The research approach is built on a literature review of business ecosystems and spatial innovation. The empirical study is based on semi-structured interviews, observations, and information gathering and verification during field research. Findings - The results include a description of the ecosystem structure and dynamics. This paper demonstrates the bottom-up nature of San Diego&apos;s health and life sciences ecosystem without a dominant lead actor, and presents prerequisites for fostering spatial ecosystems. Research limitations/implications - A single case may not be able to offer a generalized picture of this topic. However, the study raises several considerations for researchers and decision-makers involved in innovation policy design. Future work should extend the study and involve other spatial and substance contexts to compare findings and to pursue a more generic picture of innovation ecosystems and networks. Originality/value - This paper demonstrates that applying the concept of business ecosystems to the spatial context provides new insights in terms of dynamic mechanisms and factors contributing to economic growth in a particular location. Understanding how to facilitate the creation of successful spatial ecosystems is in the focal point of innovation policies."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Spatial health and life sciences business ecosystem: a case study of San Diego"/>
    <att name="name" value="67"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF INNOVATION MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="1"/>
  </node>
  <node id="35">
    <att name="AB" value="Purpose-Customer engagement (customers&apos; behavioral manifestations going beyond customer-firm purchase transactions) has been regarded as strategic imperatives for generating enhanced corporate performance. The plethora of new media has provided customers with different options to interact with firms and other customers. However, the primacy of value-laden interactive customer relationships and value cocreation raises challenges for firms and customers, especially in the context of broader business ecosystems such as brand partnership for extending value co-creation. This study aims to explore how customer engagement with well-designed choreograph of various new media&apos;s channels can increase the value cocreation extent in the context of broader business ecosystems, resulting in higher levels service offerings, experiences and innovation. Design/methodology/approach -This exploratory study presents a new framework of customer engagement that holistically integrates the elements of multiple new media and broader business ecosystem, stimulating a virtuous circle of realizing customer engagement toward superior results or innovations. The framework considers new media&apos;s different information service and technologies (e.g. search engine, social recommender, social media) that can be properly choreographed to achieve a virtuous customer engagement circle. Findings -This paper uses an exemplar framework&apos;s instantiation-an information technology enabled engagement platform (called iEngagement)-that can demonstrate how to empower the central companies together with their eco-stakeholders to holistically perform customer engagement utilizing new media toward fruitful customer engagement. Originality/value-This exploratory study is among the first that addresses the theory and practice of customer engagement within multiple new media and broader business ecosystem. This paper presents a customer engagement framework and an exemplified engagement platform that holistically integrate the elements of multiple new media and broader business ecosystem, for stimulating a virtuous circle of realizing customer engagement toward superior results or innovations."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Customer engagement within multiple new media and broader business ecosystem - a holistic perspective"/>
    <att name="name" value="35"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="KYBERNETES"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="112">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper studies the &apos;catching-up&apos; process of China&apos;s emerging wind turbine manufacturing ecosystem, and analyses the dynamics of the shifting collaborative innovation network for the period 1980-2011. We have focused on the leading wind turbine manufacturers [i.e., manufacturers of entire wind turbine system integrators (EWSIs)], as well as manufacturers of the turbines&apos; sub-ecosystems (i.e., four key component provider manufacturers: blade, gearbox, generator and control system). A network analysis method was adopted to depict the evolutionary process of the wind turbine manufacturing ecosystem. In summary, this research explores: 1) the different technology accumulation/localisation patterns in four different phases of the manufacturing ecosystem, and the collaborative innovation network; 2) the different roles and their interactions in the wind turbine manufacturing ecosystem in China; 3) the driving forces of the evolution of the wind turbine manufacturing ecosystem. The findings aim to demonstrate the evolutionary trajectory of China in terms of the &apos;catching-up&apos; of this industry, and contribute to theories of the business ecosystem lifecycle and complementary assets."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Evolution of collaborative innovation network in China&apos;s wind turbine manufacturing industry"/>
    <att name="name" value="112"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="9"/>
  </node>
  <node id="92">
    <att name="AB" value="With fast development and application, the Internet of Things (IoT) brings more opportunities to business. This research aims to investigate how IoT could lead to a co-evolving business ecosystem rather than a supply chain. It develops the 6C framework to analyze the data collected from case companies, and identifies three patterns of IoT-based business ecosystem. It also provides a summary of practical implications to guide practitioners building an IoT-based business ecosystem. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Understanding business ecosystem using a 6C framework in Internet-of-Things-based sectors"/>
    <att name="name" value="92"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRODUCTION ECONOMICS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="17"/>
  </node>
  <node id="2">
    <att name="AB" value="With the increasing significance of the business model in a connected economy, a new stream of literature has turned to explore the antecedents of business model design. Beyond external antecedents derived from a rational positioning view, little research has investigated the role of internal manufacturing flexibility. Based on theory of constraints and business ecosystem theory, this examines how manufacturing flexibility affects efficiency- and novelty-centred business model designs and consequent firm performance. We propose and test eight hypotheses using data from one hundred and eighty-six manufacturing firms in China. The results indicate that manufacturing flexibility promotes both efficiency- and novelty-centred business model designs and subsequent firm performance. Furthermore, the relationship between manufacturing flexibility and an efficiency-centred business model design is strengthened by competitive intensity but weakened by demand heterogeneity. In contrast, the relationship between manufacturing flexibility and novelty-centred business model design is weakened by competitive intensity but strengthened by demand heterogeneity."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Manufacturing flexibility, business model design, and firm performance"/>
    <att name="name" value="2"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRODUCTION ECONOMICS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="40">
    <att name="AB" value="A platform is a two-sided market. It is an environment established to allow multiple groups such as suppliers and consumers to exchange their views for fair transactions. Platforms evolve through the connection and interaction of participants, and act as ecosystems of coexistence that can provide values and benefits to all participants. Care must be taken in building such a business ecosystem to successfully stabilize the platform model. This research indicates how a business ecosystem can be constructed by analysing quality management and revenue structures - core elements in any platform business model with a distinct group of users on either side. Through 12 case studies using 30 in-depth interviews and 2 focus group interviews, this research suggests the conceptual framework, 12 different types of quality management and revenue structure strategies&apos;. These will serve as the conceptual framework from which to build platform business model ecosystems."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The platform business model and business ecosystem: quality management and revenue structures"/>
    <att name="name" value="40"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="EUROPEAN PLANNING STUDIES"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="22">
    <att name="AB" value="Innovation ecosystem is an increasingly popular but all too often ambiguously utilized concept across academia, policy and business. In their recent well-argued critique of the concept, Oh et al. (2016) called it a &quot;flawed analogy&quot; that is potentially dangerous for its lack of rigor. In this letter, we reflect on this critique and examine pathways to resolve some of the issues pointed out. We suggest that, at its best, the ecosystem analogy combines salient features from natural ecology to inform the design of system-level innovation management activities. This requires a great deal of conceptual and empirical rigor, and we outline a number of ideas for future research in this regard."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="In defense of &apos;eco&apos; in innovation ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="22"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="1">
    <att name="AB" value="Innovation is one of the increasingly important means by which companies can contribute to sustainable development. The shift of focus in business from competitiveness alone, to the combination of sustainability and competitiveness impacts firms&apos; capabilities for innovation. This process study aims to investigate what the organizational and managerial capabilities through which companies can innovate for sustainability are, referred to as dynamic capabilities for sustainable innovation. We address this question through a retrospective longitudinal case study of the attempts of the KLM Royal Dutch Airlines (KLM), which uses its influential position in the value chain to stimulate production and use of biofuel for aviation. The study identifies critical organizational and managerial capabilities that are forming the basis of the successful realignment of a firm&apos;s dynamic capabilities with its sustainable innovation strategies. We explain how these capabilities are built and strengthened for sustainable innovation and how these capabilities function throughout the development process of sustainable innovation. This study aims to contribute to a further theoretical and practical understanding of how capabilities are deployed by firms to create and implement sustainable innovation. (C) 2017 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Firms&apos; capabilities for sustainable innovation: The case of biofuel for aviation"/>
    <att name="name" value="1"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF CLEANER PRODUCTION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="18">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper unpacks resource mobilisation for biorefineries by studying investment decisions of incumbent pulp and paper firms in Sweden and Finland. The analysis highlights that the limited adoption of biorefinery technologies can be attributed to both insufficient abilities (lack of needed competencies and partnerships) and interests (preference for improving existing technologies) by pulp and paper incumbents. Drawing on the technological innovation system perspective complemented with insights from the management literature on the role of incumbents in technological change, four issues are empirically identified as important for improving resource mobilisation for biorefinery technologies: establishing loosely coupled divisions in pulp and paper firms; creating internal markets for new bioproducts aimed at further technological development; entering purchasing agreements with downstream actors; and investing in new managerial competencies."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Unpacking resource mobilisation by incumbents for biorefineries: the role of micro-level factors for technological innovation system weaknesses"/>
    <att name="name" value="18"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOLOGY ANALYSIS &amp; STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="1"/>
  </node>
  <node id="59">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper discusses some aspects of innovation in China. As China seeks to transition to a knowledge-based economy, it may become more important for China to develop innovative technologies to sustain economic growth. How do China&apos;s history, culture, institutions, and organizations aid or hinder innovation? How does China&apos;s national innovation system compare to the innovation culture in the US, as well as other developed and emerging economies? What are the prospects for the future of the Chinese national innovation system? Our starting point is the Needham Puzzle - the paradox that while China was once a world leader in technological development, it fell behind; the Industrial Revolution happened in Europe rather than in China. Potential explanations for the Needham Puzzle may shed light on the challenges facing innovation in modern China. We identify three factors that might help explain the Needham Puzzle; assess how the Needham Puzzle and Chinese culture and history have affected the modern innovation system; discuss comparative aspects of innovation ecosystems in the United States and elsewhere; and suggest that Chinese innovation emphasizes exploitation and refinement of existing knowledge to the exploration and development of new knowledge. We also discuss implications for the future of innovation in China."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The Needham Puzzle Reconsidered: Organizations, Organizing, and Innovation in China"/>
    <att name="name" value="59"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2016"/>
    <att name="SO" value="MANAGEMENT AND ORGANIZATION REVIEW"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="5"/>
  </node>
  <node id="30">
    <att name="AB" value="Technology entrepreneurs are launching and growing new businesses within business ecosystems, but little is known about how ecosystem participation impacts new venture business models. This research is an exploratory study of new venture business models within Lead To Win - a business ecosystem developed as a &apos;job-creation engine&apos; for Canada&apos;s capital region. The three-phase research design is comprised of: 1) a field study of the Lead To Win field setting; 2) a multiple case-study of participating new ventures launched by six founders; 3) development of evidence-based propositions relating ecosystem participation and new venture business models. There are two key findings. First, more intense participation in the ecosystem is associated with higher business model differentiation, sophistication, and extent of change. Second, entrepreneurs participating more intensely in the ecosystem report a greater breadth of benefits."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Business ecosystems and new venture business models: an exploratory study of participation in the Lead To Win job-creation engine"/>
    <att name="name" value="30"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="132">
    <att name="AB" value="This study focuses on value creation and capture in innovation ecosystems. It presents and discusses the findings from a qualitative, comparative case study on two European-led innovation ecosystems from the ICT and aerospace and defence sectors. The purpose of the research is to explore the tangible and intangible mechanisms related to how leading firms may facilitate value creation and capture in this context. In particular, we focus on mechanisms related to the building phase to help attract and gather relevant stakeholders, and on the management phase to help maintain and realise the business goals of all ecosystem participants. We also discuss the differences between the case industries concerning the effectiveness and usage of such mechanisms. Overall, the research findings provide new evidence on the facilitating initiatives, underlying mechanisms and structures that are related to the leading firms&apos; orchestration of innovation ecosystems."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Value creation and capture mechanisms in innovation ecosystems: a comparative case study"/>
    <att name="name" value="132"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2013"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="18"/>
  </node>
  <node id="74">
    <att name="AB" value="Product-Service Systems (PSSs) constitute a family of service-based business models designed to satisfy our societal needs in an economically and environmentally sustainable manner. To date however PSS application has remained niche due to a variety of critical barriers. This paper explores how &apos;demand pull&apos; national government policies could support PSS activity by addressing these barriers and cultivating market demand. Lessons are drawn from a case study of how regulatory, economic incentive, informative and procurement policies have supported Energy Service Company (ESCo) activity in the UK; a sub-set of the PSS family focused on energy service provision. Subsequently five policy recommendations are presented to support PSS activity: (1) balancing economic incentives and regulatory disincentives; (2) promoting indirect policy support; (3) redesigning existing market structures; (4) promoting locally-led PSS activity; and (5) creating stable policy frameworks. The paper warns however that national government policy cannot easily address all PSS barriers, such as customer preferences, international developments, technological progress and inherent business model weaknesses, pointing to the need for other complementary solutions. Furthermore, other governance actors beside national government could also implement PSS supporting policies. (C) 2015 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="&apos;Demand pull&apos; government policies to support Product-Service System activity: the case of Energy Service Companies (ESCos) in the UK"/>
    <att name="name" value="74"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF CLEANER PRODUCTION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="12"/>
  </node>
  <node id="168">
    <att name="AB" value="Most firms competing in the global economy are paying increasing attention to innovation as the key driver of competitiveness. Innovation&apos;s key dimensions address the quality, the quantity and the speed of introducing innovations. With an increasing rate of change in the global economy, especially after the onset of the 2008-2009 economic crisis, innovation management emerges as a powerful way to facilitate a firm&apos;s adaptation to new conditions. However, despite a widespread acceptance of innovation&apos;s importance by the leadership of most companies, there is a general dissatisfaction with the results realised from innovation investments. For any organisation to address effectively the innovation challenge, its leadership must properly define the innovation system and process and apply sound quality and innovation management principles, as was done in the development of quality management and finance management. This requires the periodic assessment not only of innovation outputs, i.e. new products, services or business models, but also of inputs that determine a firm&apos;s innovation capability and the innovation process itself. Managing the effectiveness of the innovation process requires a balanced set of innovation metrics related to all innovation drivers, i.e. leadership, culture and people participation together with innovation results, such as time to market and financial metrics. This paper describes an integrated framework for the systematic assessment of an organisation&apos;s quality, i.e. value-generating capability of its innovation management and the timely identification of ways to measure and improve it."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="A framework for the assessment of an organisation&apos;s innovation excellence"/>
    <att name="name" value="168"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2010"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TOTAL QUALITY MANAGEMENT &amp; BUSINESS EXCELLENCE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="26"/>
  </node>
  <node id="95">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper examines the relationship between biomedical policies and entrepreneurial R&amp;D strategies. Public health programs have been unable to provide effective and affordable treatment of infectious diseases for the poor. While governments have become more open to private sector contributions to policy objectives, it is rare to find new ventures commercializing healthcare innovations for neglected diseases. Two case studies of entrepreneurial ventures, in the UK and China, provide evidence on how resource-constrained firms mobilize participants in policy-specific ecosystems to achieve their goals of new vaccine development for tuberculosis. Ecosystem analysis reveals how the innovators&apos; business models can align their strategies with national policy objectives. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Policy-driven ecosystems for new vaccine development"/>
    <att name="name" value="95"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOVATION"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="1"/>
  </node>
  <node id="104">
    <att name="AB" value="The UK energy technology innovation system (ETIS) has undergone wholesale remaking in recent years, in terms of its aims, funding and organisation. We analyse this process and distinguish between three phases since 2000: new beginnings, momentum building and urgency and review. Within an international trend to ETIS rebuilding, UK experience has been distinctive: from a low starting base in the early-2000s, to system remaking under a strong decarbonisation policy imperative in the late-2000s, to multiple and contested drivers in the early-2010s. Public funding levels have been erratic, with a rapid increase and a more recent decline. The private business sector has played a leading role in this remaking, and as this influence has grown, the role and style of energy innovation has shifted from long term niches to the shorter term mainstream. The UK ETIS suffers from persistent problems: fragmentation, low transparency and weak links to the research evidence base. (C) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd. This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/)."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Remaking the UK&apos;s energy technology innovation system: From the margins to the mainstream"/>
    <att name="name" value="104"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="ENERGY POLICY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="7"/>
  </node>
  <node id="153">
    <att name="AB" value="Carbon capture and storage (CCS) is increasingly depicted as an important element of the carbon dioxide mitigation portfolio. However, critics have warned that CCS might lead to &quot;reinforced fossil fuel lock-in&quot;, by perpetuating a fossil fuel based energy provision system. Due to large-scale investments in CCS infrastructure, the fossil fuel based &apos;regime&apos; would be perpetuated to at least the end of this century. In this paper we investigate if and how CCS could help to avoid reinforcing fossil fuel lock-in. First we develop a set of criteria to estimate the degree of technological lock-in. We apply these criteria to assess the lock-in reinforcement effect of adding CCS to the fossil fuel socio-technical regime (FFR). In principle, carbon dioxide could be captured from any carbon dioxide point source. In the practice of present technological innovations, business strategies, and policy developments, CCS is most often coupled to coal power plants. However, there are many point sources of carbon dioxide that are not directly related to coal or even fossil fuels. For instance, many forms of bio-energy or biomass-based processes generate significant streams of carbon dioxide emissions. Capturing this carbon dioxide which was originally sequestered in biomass could lead to negative carbon dioxide emissions. We use the functional approach of technical innovations systems (TIS) to estimate in more detail the strengths of the &quot;niches&quot; CCS and Bio-Energy with CCS (BECCS). We also assess the orientation of the CCS niche towards the FFR and the risk of crowding out BECCS. Next we develop pathways for developing fossil energy carbon capture and storage, BECCS, and combinations of them, using transition pathways concepts. The outcome is that a large-scale BECCS development could be feasible under certain conditions, thus largely avoiding the risk of reinforced fossil fuel lock-in. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Carbon capture and storage, bio-energy with carbon capture and storage, and the escape from the fossil-fuel lock-in"/>
    <att name="name" value="153"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2011"/>
    <att name="SO" value="GLOBAL ENVIRONMENTAL CHANGE-HUMAN AND POLICY DIMENSIONS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="28"/>
  </node>
  <node id="33">
    <att name="AB" value="Purpose - The sharing of knowledge between partners in collaborative relationships is widely accepted to be fundamental to supporting strategic decision making, particularly in relation to innovation management and business sustainability. The purpose of this paper is to focus on how the structure of collaborative relationships in business networks may determine successful knowledge sharing and thus improve decision making and business performance. Design/methodology/approach - Expert interviews were conducted with participants operating in networks and business ecosystem in four different sectors in Italy and Germany, exploring the process of knowledge sharing, organisational learning and decision making within collaborative relationships. A qualitative textual analysis was used to analyse the experts&apos; responses. Findings - The research found that an organisation&apos;s network position and the network structure, as well as the governance and richness of the business ecosystem in which it operates, influence its ability to share knowledge, to innovate and therefore to compete sustainably. Research limitations/implications - The research demonstrates that innovative strategic decision making, based on access to appropriate knowledge, occurs within the context of social and business network relations operating within a broader more diverse business ecosystem. Closer dyadic or small working group ties best facilitate trust and sharing of the most valuable knowledge. Appropriate participation in and management of such structures is therefore essential to support knowledge-based decision making, and critical to sustained competitive advantage. Originality/value - The research focusses on how interfirm relationships are established and maintained, how firms establish trust and facilitate knowledge sharing forming the basis of organisational learning."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Knowledge sharing and collaborative relationships in business ecosystems and networks A definition and a demarcation"/>
    <att name="name" value="33"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT &amp; DATA SYSTEMS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="6">
    <att name="AB" value="Recently, business ecosystems have been recognized as one of the most interesting phenomenon in software engineering research. Companies experience a paradigm shift where product development and innovation is moving outside the boundaries of the firm and where networks of stakeholders join forces to co-create value. While there is prominent research focusing on the managerial perspective of business ecosystems, few studies provide strategic guidance for how to intentionally manage the different ecosystems that companies operate in. Therefore, and on the basis of multicase study research, we provide empirical evidence on the challenges that software-intensive companies experience in relation to the different types of business ecosystems they operate in. We conduct a state-of-the-art literature review to identify strategies that are used to manage ecosystem engagements, and we develop a conceptual model in which we identify strategies for managing the innovation ecosystem, the differentiating ecosystem, and the commoditizing ecosystem. By categorising the different strategies in relation to the different types of ecosystems for which they are valid, the three-layer ecosystem strategy model provides comprehensive support for strategy selection. We validate the use of the identified strategies in 6 software-intensive case companies, and we provide empirical insights on the relevance and the desired use of these strategies as experienced by the case companies."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="From ad hoc to strategic ecosystem management: the &quot;Three-Layer Ecosystem Strategy Model&quot; (TeLESM)"/>
    <att name="name" value="6"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF SOFTWARE-EVOLUTION AND PROCESS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="73">
    <att name="AB" value="Nowadays, the use of purposive inflows and outflows of knowledge to accelerate internal innovation and to expand the markets for external use of innovation has become essential in business strategies and national policies. In addition, the importance of knowledge and technology diffusion requires better understanding of knowledge networks and national innovation systems (NISs). We want to answer the following research question: what kinds of effects will occur in NISs if different levels of open innovation policies are introduced into NISs? According to our literature review, perfect open innovation policies should have three aspects: knowledge and technology production, distribution and consumption. We built a causal loop diagram and a system dynamics model to simulate the effects of open innovation policies on NISs and apply the results to the case of Cambodia to develop Cambodia&apos;s national science and technology master plan."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Analysing and simulating the effects of open innovation policies: Application of the results to Cambodia"/>
    <att name="name" value="73"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="SCIENCE AND PUBLIC POLICY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="2"/>
  </node>
  <node id="91">
    <att name="AB" value="Purpose - The purpose of this paper is to provide a framework for understanding core technological competencies and identifying the trends on the technological convergence of a business ecosystem using the patent information of leading firms in the system. Design/methodology/approach - The proposed framework is composed of two steps: time-sequential text clustering analysis for comprehending changes in general technological fields and association rule analysis for identifying the trends of convergences in each field. The authors applied the proposed framework to the patents applied to United States Patent Trademark Office by Samsung Electronics, a market leader of the electronics industry, during the period from 2000 to 2011. Findings - In the sequential text clustering analysis, trends of 14 technological fields such as data storage medium and data processing, mobile, lights and heats and memory are identified. Moreover, changes of technological convergence in each field are identified using association rule analysis. For instance, in the case of technologies related to lights and heats, convergences occurred between radio transmission systems and modulated-carrier systems during the period from 2000 to 2001. However, recent convergences appeared between technologies regarding controlling lights and liquid crystal materials since 2008. Originality/value - Utilization of the framework will suggest new business opportunities to SMEs in a business ecosystem by identifying the trends of technological convergences."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Analyzing technological convergence trends in a business ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="91"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2015"/>
    <att name="SO" value="INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT &amp; DATA SYSTEMS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="2"/>
  </node>
  <node id="37">
    <att name="AB" value="Purpose - The purpose of this paper is to clarify the relationship between start-ups and an innovation ecosystem. Start-ups need resources available in the ecosystem to grow, but experience organizational capacity limitations during their open innovation practices. This study frames the &quot;open innovation&quot; interface and discloses ways to accelerate the process of connecting start-ups&apos; demands to ecosystem&apos;s supplies. Design/methodology/approach - A case study was used to describe the development of a conceptual ecosystem model to frame the &quot;open innovation&quot; interface and its subsequent implementation at nine start-up hotspots in the Dutch chemical industry. To develop the ecosystem model, the system of innovation concept was enriched with the perspective of a chemical start-up to pinpoint critical resources for growth. Findings - It is suggested that the most relevant &quot;open innovation&quot; interface for start-ups looking to grow is an innovation biotope: a well-defined, business-oriented cross-section of an ecosystem. All stakeholders in a biotope are carefully selected based on the entrepreneurial issue at stake: they can only enter the secured marketplace if they are able to provide dedicated solutions to start-ups. The biotope enables &quot;open innovation in a closed system&quot; which results in acceleration of the innovation process. Originality/value - This is the first study to report on the definition and implementation of an innovation biotope as the &quot;open innovation&quot; interface between an ecosystem and start-ups. In addition, it provides a powerful tool, the ecosystem canvas, that can help both regional and national innovation systems to visualize their ecosystem and identify blind spots."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Accelerating chemical start-ups in ecosystems: the need for biotopes"/>
    <att name="name" value="37"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF INNOVATION MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="105">
    <att name="AB" value="This paper brings together the recent literature on industry platforms and shows how it relates to managing innovation within and outside the firm as well as to dealing with technological and market disruptions and change over time. First, we identify distinct types of platforms. Our analysis of a wide range of industry examples suggests that there are two predominant types of platforms: internal or company-specific platforms, and external or industry-wide platforms. We define internal (company or product) platforms as a set of assets organized in a common structure from which a company can efficiently develop and produce a stream of derivative products. We define external (industry) platforms as products, services, or technologies that act as a foundation upon which external innovators, organized as an innovative business ecosystem, can develop their own complementary products, technologies, or services. Second, we summarize from the literature general propositions on the design, economics, and strategic management of platforms. Third, we review the case of Intel and other examples to illustrate the range of technological, strategic, and business challenges that platform leaders and their competitors face as markets and technologies evolve. Finally, we identify practices associated with effective platform leadership and avenues for future research to deepen our understanding of this important phenomenon and what firms can do to manage platform-related competition and innovation."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Industry Platforms and Ecosystem Innovation"/>
    <att name="name" value="105"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF PRODUCT INNOVATION MANAGEMENT"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="69"/>
  </node>
  <node id="156">
    <att name="AB" value="Today, the idea that random collisions and interactions offer solutions and business opportunities is no longer acceptable. Instead, partnerships and alignments, both downstream and upstream, are paramount for cross-fertilization and synergy. To survive, and thrive, in today&apos;s world of global innovation, alliances based on compatible differences must be sought. Innovation Partnerships and the Sharing-is-Winning model represent a paradigm shift toward accelerating co-development of sustainable innovation, with alignment of the entire value chain with consumer-centric innovations being one of its main pillars. It includes 3 levels of typical joint development: universities, research institutes, and centers; start-ups and individual inventors; a select number of key strategic suppliers. Reinventing R&amp;D in an open innovation ecosystem and increasing success rates in an increasingly competitive marketplace require implementing significant steps-both perceived and tangible. Specific recommendations are provided for 10 major identified topics: leadership, strategy, the consumer, the value chain, internal experts and championship, metrics, IP, culture, academia, and passion. The Sharing-is-Winning model extends the scope of open innovation to sustainable and enhanced processes of co-innovation."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Reinventing R&amp;D in an Open Innovation Ecosystem"/>
    <att name="name" value="156"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2011"/>
    <att name="SO" value="JOURNAL OF FOOD SCIENCE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="23"/>
  </node>
  <node id="128">
    <att name="AB" value="The study considers the interdependencies between complementors in the business ecosystem and explores the nature of collaborative interactions between them. It sheds light on the organizational and the strategic contexts in which such interactions take place, and shows how they may influence the pattern and the benefits of collaboration. The evidence presented is based on fieldwork followed by a detailed survey instrument administered to firms in the semiconductor industry. The findings, while reinforcing the shift in the locus of value creation from focal firms to collaborative business ecosystems characterized by information sharing and joint action among complementors, illustrate the organizational and the competitive challenges that firms face in their pursuit of joint value creation."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="COLLABORATING WITH COMPLEMENTORS: WHAT DO FIRMS DO?"/>
    <att name="name" value="128"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2013"/>
    <att name="SO" value="COLLABORATION AND COMPETITION IN BUSINESS ECOSYSTEMS"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="8"/>
  </node>
  <node id="12">
    <att name="AB" value="Previous studies discuss how regulatory, technological and market drivers increasingly challenge manufacturing industries to adopt eco-innovations. However, the understanding of the process by which eco-innovations are developed and commercialized as a result of these drivers is not yet well established, in particular because these drivers are perceived differently by the end-users and their suppliers. In this paper, we address the following research question: How do eco-innovation drivers shape processes in value-creating networks? To answer this question, we carried out a case study purposely selected to understand how eco-innovation drivers, such as regulation, market pull and technology, interact and affect the eco-innovation decisions in a given industry. We analyzed the processes in an eco-innovation initiative about retrofitting old ships, contextualized in the maritime equipment and supply industry. The paper makes two novel contributions: First, we develop a framework that can support supply-network eco-innovation initiatives to deal with changes at the regulatory, market and technology levels. The framework includes elements, such as value co-creation to explore technological opportunities emerging from the interaction of the drivers or value proposition development to align multiple actors&apos; interests in the network and agree on shared expectations to exploit the opportunities. Second, we contribute to the emerging research area on eco-innovation processes by highlighting the lesser-known role of value-creating network dynamics. Value-creating networks can be a platform for the development of more radical eco-innovations if actors in the networks can align their value creation and capture objectives."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Eco-Innovation Drivers in Value-Creating Networks: A Case Study of Ship Retrofitting Services"/>
    <att name="name" value="12"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="SUSTAINABILITY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <node id="99">
    <att name="AB" value="The food industry, and especially small and medium enterprises in that industry, are faced with numerous complex challenges that open innovation addresses. The main topics reviewed here are: adapting open innovation for the food industry&apos;s special needs, small and medium enterprises&apos; unique challenges, open innovation solution providers, the roles of academia and the intellectual properties model. Some specific recommendations include: collaboration, creation of a new innovation ecosystem (industry, academia, government and private business), metrics to quantify academia&apos;s social responsibility and revised curricula promoting open innovation and innovation, small and medium enterprise involvement, a new intellectual properties model, and management mindsets and strategies. Open innovation is an opportunity for all stake-holders to proactively engage in meeting future challenges and opportunities."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="Challenges in exploiting open innovation&apos;s full potential in the food industry with a focus on small and medium enterprises (SMEs)"/>
    <att name="name" value="99"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2014"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TRENDS IN FOOD SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="19"/>
  </node>
  <node id="10">
    <att name="AB" value="During the past few decades, the configurations of new knowledge-intensive environments have required fertile settings for innovative and entrepreneurial activities. In these environments, Triple Helix has been operationalized in different ways, spaces, and contexts where those agents are transforming their roles in the development and strengthening of national innovation and entrepreneurial ecosystems. As a consequence, the phenomenon of entrepreneurial innovations emerged from enterprises with an entrepreneurial or high-growth orientation that collaborate with Triple Helix agents generating economic benefits and spillover effects. In emerging economies, the available literature about innovation and entrepreneurship is limited to explore the determinants of innovation performance as well as innovation constrains. Based on this argument and diverging from prior research, this research tries to provide a better understanding about the influence of Triple Helix agents on entrepreneurial innovations&apos; performance of enterprises located in emerging economies. In particular, we analyze the effects produced by the links of enterprises with other enterprises, universities and government on their innovation performance (e.g., access to knowledge/technology, sources of funding, government subsidies), as well as, the moderation effects generated when those enterprises have a high-growth orientation (e.g., distinction of enterprises that develop entrepreneurial innovations or traditional innovations). To achieve this aim we look inside at the case of Mexico because is an emerging economy that during the last two decades has facing a transition to a knowledge-based economy. Using a cross-section dataset of 19,188 Mexican enterprises interviewed in the period of 2006 to 2012, we tested our proposed conceptual model with a Tobit regression. Our study provides interesting implications for the main actors involved in the Mexican Science, Technology and Innovation System, as well as, contributes about the debate of the impact of enterprises-university-government linkages on entrepreneurial innovations from diverse perspectives and research fields (e.g., open innovation, knowledge transfer, high-growth entrepreneurship, academic entrepreneurship, public entrepreneurship). (C) 2016 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved."/>
    <att name="classID" value="0"/>
    <att name="TI" value="The impact of Triple Helix agents on entrepreneurial innovations&apos; performance: An inside look at enterprises located in an emerging economy"/>
    <att name="name" value="10"/>
    <att name="PY" value="2017"/>
    <att name="SO" value="TECHNOLOGICAL FORECASTING AND SOCIAL CHANGE"/>
    <att name="Z9" value="0"/>
  </node>
  <!-- edges -->
  <edge source="1" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="136" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="138" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="150" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="155" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="164" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="176" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="181" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="187" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="192" target="192">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="101" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="118" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="129">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="129" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="17">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="17">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="17">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="17">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="17">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="17">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="17">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="17">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="17">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="35">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="17" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="131">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="131">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="131">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="131">  </edge>
  <edge source="131" target="131">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="82">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="83">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="82" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="76">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="83">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="76" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="21">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="21">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="21">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="35">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="21" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="34">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="34">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="34">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="34">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="34">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="34" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="42">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="83">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="42" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="4">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="4">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="4">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="5">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="35">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="59">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="4" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="89">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="89" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="13">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="13">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="13">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="13">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="13">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="13">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="14">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="15">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="13" target="190">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="59" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="77">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="77" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="83" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="133" target="133">  </edge>
  <edge source="133" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="133" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="133" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="133" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="29">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="35">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="49">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="29" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="46">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="46" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="31">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="31">  </edge>
  <edge source="31" target="31">  </edge>
  <edge source="31" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="31" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="31" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="31" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="55" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="87">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="87" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="108" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="134" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="150" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="176" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="187" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="188" target="188">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="98">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="98" target="190">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="14">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="14">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="14">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="14">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="14">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="14">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="14">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="15">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="18">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="25">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="49">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="14" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="136" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="150" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="155" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="158" target="158">  </edge>
  <edge source="158" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="158" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="99" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="108" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="150" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="164" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="176" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="181" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="187" target="187">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="59" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="99" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="108" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="110" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="118" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="150" target="150">  </edge>
  <edge source="150" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="150" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="150" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="47">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="49">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="118">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="47" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="134" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="136" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="155" target="155">  </edge>
  <edge source="155" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="155" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="155" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="110" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="134" target="134">  </edge>
  <edge source="134" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="134" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="134" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="134" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="61">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="72">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="83">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="61" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="59" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="108" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="110" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="126">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="126" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="59" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="90">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="118">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="90" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="0">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="3">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="5">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="8">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="10">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="0" target="190">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="164" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="171" target="171">  </edge>
  <edge source="171" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="97" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="138" target="138">  </edge>
  <edge source="138" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="138" target="170">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="8">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="8">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="8">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="8">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="8">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="8">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="15">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="8" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="38">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="49">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="118">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="38" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="19" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="50">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="50" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="59" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="65">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="65" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="19" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="62">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="62" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="66">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="66" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="164" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="168" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="176" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="181" target="181">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="39">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="39" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="97" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="104" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="108" target="108">  </edge>
  <edge source="108" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="108" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="108" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="81">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="81" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="101" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="106">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="106" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="25">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="25">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="25">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="25">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="25">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="25" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="136" target="136">  </edge>
  <edge source="136" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="136" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="45">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="83">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="45" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="118">  </edge>
  <edge source="104" target="118">  </edge>
  <edge source="118" target="118">  </edge>
  <edge source="118" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="118" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="28">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="28" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="99" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="109">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="109" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="55">  </edge>
  <edge source="55" target="55">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="19" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="59" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="101" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="103">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="103" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="49">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="49">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="49">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="49">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="49">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="49" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="5">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="5">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="5">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="5">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="6">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="15">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="5" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="3">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="3">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="3">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="6">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="10">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="12">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="15">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="18">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="59">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="3" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="64">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="64" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="59" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="101" target="101">  </edge>
  <edge source="101" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="101" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="97" target="97">  </edge>
  <edge source="97" target="104">  </edge>
  <edge source="97" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="97" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="15">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="15">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="15">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="15">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="15" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="110" target="110">  </edge>
  <edge source="72" target="72">  </edge>
  <edge source="72" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="156" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="164" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="176" target="176">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="96">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="96" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="80">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="80" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="27">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="27" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="164" target="164">  </edge>
  <edge source="164" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="122">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="122" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="79">  </edge>
  <edge source="79" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="67">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="67" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="35">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="35">  </edge>
  <edge source="35" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="112">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="112" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="92">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="92" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="2">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="2">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="6">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="10">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="12">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="19">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="59">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="2" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="40">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="40" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="22">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="22" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="1">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="12">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="18">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="19">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="83">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="104">  </edge>
  <edge source="1" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="18">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="18">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="83">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="104">  </edge>
  <edge source="18" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="59">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="59">  </edge>
  <edge source="59" target="59">  </edge>
  <edge source="59" target="170">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="30">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="30" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="99" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="132" target="132">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="74">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="83">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="104">  </edge>
  <edge source="74" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="156" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="168" target="168">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="95">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="95" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="104" target="104">  </edge>
  <edge source="104" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="153" target="153">  </edge>
  <edge source="153" target="190">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="33">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="33" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="6">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="6" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="73">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="73" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="91">  </edge>
  <edge source="91" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="37">  </edge>
  <edge source="37" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="99" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="105">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="105" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="99" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="156" target="156">  </edge>
  <edge source="128" target="128">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="12">  </edge>
  <edge source="12" target="83">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="99" target="99">  </edge>
  <edge source="10" target="10">  </edge>
</graph>
